<singleQueryResults queryID="1003">
  <documents>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1209wb-32-28008">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="0">
          <content>The idea that "everyone's doing it" can influence some kids to leave their better judgment, or their common sense, behind.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="1">
          <content>Walking Away From Peer Pressure</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="2">
          <content>Talking to a parent, teacher, or school counselor can help you feel much better and prepare you for the next time you face peer pressure.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="3">
          <content>Powerful, Positive Peer Pressure</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="4">
          <content>ALL of us are cutting math.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="5">
          <content>Let's talk about how to handle it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="6">
          <content>Paying attention to your own feelings and beliefs about what is right and wrong can help you know the right thing to do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="7">
          <content>Inner strength and self-confidence can help you stand firm, walk away, and resist doing something when you know better.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="8">
          <content>It can really help to have at least one other peer, or friend, who is willing to say "no," too.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="9">
          <content>It's great to have friends with values similar to yours who will back you up when you don't want to do something.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="10">
          <content>If you choose friends who don't use drugs , cut class, smoke cigarettes, or lie to their parents, then you probably won't do these things either, even if other kids do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="11">
          <content>Try to help a friend who's having trouble resisting peer pressure.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="12">
          <content>It can be powerful for one kid to join another by simply saying, "I'm with you - let's go."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="13">
          <content>Even if you're faced with peer pressure while you're alone, there are still things you can do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="14">
          <content>You can simply stay away from peers who pressure you to do stuff you know is wrong.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="15">
          <content>You can tell them "no" and walk away.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="16">
          <content>Better yet, find other friends and classmates to pal around with.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="17">
          <content>If you continue to face peer pressure and you're finding it difficult to handle, talk to someone you trust.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="18">
          <content>Don't feel guilty if you've made a mistake or two.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="19">
          <content>For example, positive peer pressure can be used to pressure bullies into acting better toward other kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="20">
          <content>If enough kids get together, peers can pressure each other into doing what's right!</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0400tw-90-00591">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="21">
          <content>If you or someone you know is bothered by a bully, talk to someone you trust.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="22">
          <content>Everyone has the right to feel safe, and being bullied makes people feel unsafe.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="23">
          <content>Tell someone about it and keep telling until something is done.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="24">
          <content>Bullying can make kids not want to play outside or go to school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="25">
          <content>You can't go into hiding or skip class, of course.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="26">
          <content>But if you can take a different route and avoid him or her, do so.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="27">
          <content>Make a plan to walk with a friend or two on the way to school or recess or lunch or wherever you think you might meet the bully.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1209wb-17-23859">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="28">
          <content>For example, a few kids in school might try to get you to cut class with them, your soccer friend might try to convince you to be mean to another player and never pass her the ball, or a kid in the neighborhood might want you to shoplift with him.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0005wb-45-11023">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="29">
          <content>Bullying is a big problem.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="30">
          <content>Bullying can make school a place of fear and can lead to more violence and more stress for everyone.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="31">
          <content>If so, you could decide to get up a little earlier so you can be clean and refreshed for the school day.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="32">
          <content>Teachers, counselors, and parents can help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="33">
          <content>It's hard to keep your mind on schoolwork when you're worried about how you're going to deal with the bully near your locker.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="34">
          <content>As much as you can, avoid the bully.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="35">
          <content>Stand tall and be brave.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="36">
          <content>When you're scared of another person, you're probably not feeling your bravest.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="37">
          <content>But sometimes just acting brave is enough to stop a bully.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="38">
          <content>Stand tall and you'll send the message: "Don't mess with me."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="39">
          <content>It's easier to feel brave when you feel good about yourself.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="40">
          <content>If so, maybe you'll decide to get more exercise, watch less TV, and eat healthier snacks.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="41">
          <content>Or maybe you feel you look best when you shower in the morning before school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="42">
          <content>Two is better than one if you're trying to avoid being bullied.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="43">
          <content>Offer to do the same if a friend is having bully trouble.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="44">
          <content>Ignore the bully.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="45">
          <content>If you can, try your best to ignore the bully's threats.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="46">
          <content>Pretend you don't hear them and walk away quickly to a place of safety.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="47">
          <content>Acting as if you don't notice and don't care is like giving no reaction at all, and this just might stop a bully's behavior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="48">
          <content>Stand up for yourself.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="49">
          <content>Pretend to feel really brave and confident.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="50">
          <content>Tell the bully "No!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="51">
          <content>Then walk away, or run if you have to.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="52">
          <content>If a bully wants you to do something that you don't want to do - say "no!"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="53">
          <content>and walk away.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="54">
          <content>Bullies tend to bully kids who don't stick up for themselves.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="55">
          <content>Don't bully back.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="56">
          <content>Don't hit, kick, or push back to deal with someone bullying you or your friends.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="57">
          <content>How can you stop yourself from getting angry or showing you're upset?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="58">
          <content>Try distracting yourself (counting backwards from 100, spelling the word 'turtle' backwards, etc.) to keep your mind occupied until you are out of the situation and somewhere safe where you can show your feelings.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="59">
          <content>Tell an adult.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="60">
          <content>If you are being bullied, it's very important to tell an adult.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="61">
          <content>Find someone you trust and go and tell them what is happening to you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="62">
          <content>Teachers, principals, parents, and lunchroom helpers at school can all help to stop bullying.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="63">
          <content>Sometimes bullies stop as soon as a teacher finds out because they're afraid that they will be punished by parents.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0508wb-29-03424">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="64">
          <content>If you have a disability that affects how you learn, you may be put in a mainstream class but be given extra attention to help you learn.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="65">
          <content>If you are in a mainstream class, it is because you, your parents, and your teachers have decided it's the best place for you to learn.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="66">
          <content>If you start out in a mainstream class and then get moved to a special education class, it may be hard to adjust.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="67">
          <content>You are moving to a special education class because you will be able to learn better there.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="68">
          <content>Besides teaching the usual school subjects, many schools also offer special classes for kids with disabilities to help them learn life skills.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="69">
          <content>Figure out where you want to go in life and how you're going to get there</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1410wb-37-21744">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="70">
          <content>But no one needs to put up with a bully's behavior.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0003wb-45-24393">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="71">
          <content>Or, you may be put in a special education class with other kids who have disabilities.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="72">
          <content>If something is out of your reach or you have a question about the assignment, don't be afraid to ask.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="73">
          <content>Figure out your strengths and needs</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1209wb-32-28022">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="74">
          <content>We think so, but what do we mean when we say "kids with special needs"?</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1209wb-17-23860">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="75">
          <content>This means any kid who might need extra help because of a medical, emotional, or learning problem.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="76">
          <content>You might be able to spot a few kids with special needs, but you probably don't notice all of them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="77">
          <content>By being a friend.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0601wb-34-04091">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="78">
          <content>As a teacher/school counselor since 1985, I had a handful of students who really tried my nerves at times.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="79">
          <content>Classroom management is key, but dealing with your own underlying emotions related to a particular student is just as important.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="80">
          <content>So, what to do with kids whose delay tactics include skipping in late, fiddling with their books, and then moseying out of their seats?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="81">
          <content>"Having lots of established procedures is key," says Kate Ortiz.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="82">
          <content>"When the bell rings, everything but [class] materials must be stowed, and there's an assignment on the overhead...usually three or four review questions and it's very effective because it's graded."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="83">
          <content>Ortiz also writes every name on a clipboard and walks around, tallying misbehavior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="84">
          <content>Dave Foley, a retiree from Michigan with 29 years of experience, wrote the book (literally) on discipline-with chapters that you might appreciate, like, "Using the Stay-After-Class Threat Effectively," or "Using Peer Pressure to Improve Behavior."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="85">
          <content>"The experienced teacher takes it off the table by taking it off the table right away," Burke says.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="86">
          <content>"And you've got to be consistent.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="87">
          <content>If it's Friday afternoon and the kids are taking a test, and the first kid done says, 'Can I listen to my iPod?'</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="88">
          <content>If you answer yes, it's a progressive loss of territory.... You don't have to be a jerk.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="89">
          <content>Just say, 'I have to be clear.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="90">
          <content>This is school policy.'"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="91">
          <content>And always follow school policy.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="92">
          <content>Try to commit to two minutes at the beginning of each class to touch base with the often-angry student, Buley suggests.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="93">
          <content>"Prime the pump for the day-ask 'How is the day going to go today?'"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="94">
          <content>Was everybody nice at the bus stop?"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="95">
          <content>For older kids, you could ask, "How has your day been?"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="96">
          <content>Pay attention to the things that make them unique.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="97">
          <content>"When you can talk to them about the fact that they go to the skate park every weekend, you're modeling that they're not a paper cutout."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="98">
          <content>The Time Gobblers</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="99">
          <content>If you're a secondary school teacher with a 45-minute period, you know every click counts.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="100">
          <content>They have 10 "self-starting points" a week and they do figure into final grades.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="101">
          <content>And, for those kids who pack up early?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="102">
          <content>Dave Foley, author of the Ultimate Classroom Control Handbook, has a neat trick.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="103">
          <content>With a few minutes left, close the door.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="104">
          <content>Firmly.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="105">
          <content>And say, "We really need to finish this lesson....I'll close the door so you won't be distracted by people passing in the halls."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="106">
          <content>Aaagh!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="107">
          <content>That's prime socializing time!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="108">
          <content>"The core thing is, find out what they don't want to happen and make it a possibility."</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0601wb-97-33680">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="109">
          <content>It is especially important not to corner a kid, especially a potentially violent high school student, as that is when a teacher puts the whole class at a safety risk.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="110">
          <content>If students continued to challenge the school, they were sent to reformatories,Boys Towns, Girls Towns etc.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="111">
          <content>Guidelines were clear and teachers helped students to live by common sense, civil rules.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="112">
          <content>When teachers are told to deal with the situation in such mild "paliative" measures year after year, it is almost an insult as they will continue to waste horrible amounts of time with little success in the classroom until the deeper structural questions are dealt with, like where to put those students who continue to disrupt so the rest of the kids can learn.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="113">
          <content>Anyone who disrupted the class was asked to leave.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="114">
          <content>I have always treated students with respect using the techniques in this article, but in some situations, they simply did not work and I had to be honest about the lack of educational quality offered to those who trully wanted to learn.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="115">
          <content>Teachers can do anything from a simple science experiment or a game that connects students' lives to the lesson.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="116">
          <content>"The teacher who asks challenging questions stimulates student interest.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="117">
          <content>Empower your students by encouraging them to participate in activities of the whole group or in smaller groups."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="118">
          <content>If teachers can start to understand students' cultures better, a partnership can be formed between school and the home with the parents.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="119">
          <content>If the primary problem is one child's behavior, you can talk to him or her in private, but as long as the student isn't disrupting the class, it's not worth stopping instruction to address a situation.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="120">
          <content>As some have already alluded, calling home can be a miracle worker.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="121">
          <content>When groups refuse to work, I telephone their parents at the first opportunity during the day, or send an email.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="122">
          <content>When I telephone home, I make sure that I begin the conversation complimenting what the student does well, and I assure parents that I like their child, enjoy having them in the class; I really praise a student?s excellent qualities; yet, there?s just this one problem... Furthermore, circulating around the class room, "assisting" also works.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="123">
          <content>There's always an assignment they "should be" attempting to complete.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="124">
          <content>When groups decide something other than the immediate task needs to be discussed, I "visit" EACH one, inquire about the status of their assignment, look it over and see if I can offer any suggestions on how to improve, or any general advice pertaining to the completion of the task at hand.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="125">
          <content>When I approach such students, I don?t mention that they are talking and not doing their work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="126">
          <content>Therein lies my opportunity to assess if they truly understand what they are to do and to motivate them in any way that I can to get it done.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="127">
          <content>Students need to be taught respect from home.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="128">
          <content>I usually take the disruptive student aside and have a one on one conversation.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="129">
          <content>My expectations are restated and for the most part the student understand what is expected and what is not tolerated.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="130">
          <content>The school administration is the key.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="131">
          <content>If their child continues to disrupt class; he parent should be compelled to attend a conference on that student's behalf.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="132">
          <content>In middle school wwe try to teach the student that it is now their responsibility to make the right choices.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="133">
          <content>If they choose to behave that way, they will serve detention, Saturday school, or another appropriate consequence.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="134">
          <content>Now I send each disruptive student an e-mail with a cc to the parent.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="135">
          <content>When the parent is supportive of my role as an instructor, compliance and respect increase accordingly.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="136">
          <content>Are we presenting material in ways that encourage kids to care?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="137">
          <content>After a telephone call home, often there?s a complete personality transformation; a few never disrupt again for the remainder of the school year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="138">
          <content>So often, just giving them an attn shift seems to do the trick.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="139">
          <content>It's important to keep in contact with the parent,but it's difficult when they don't support you at home.Middle school students are very disrespectful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="140">
          <content>Teachers will meet and discuss the best alternative for that child, Please note, An IEP or 504 does not mean a parent is off the hook for their child's behavior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="141">
          <content>I agree with keeping up on parent contacts.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="142">
          <content>It's imperative to let them know what's going on and see if they have any suggestions.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="143">
          <content>I have so many that told me how grateful they were that I had called and let them know!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="144">
          <content>What happened to calling the parents to enlist their support?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="145">
          <content>Complementing the positive traits before discussing the negatives usually worked well.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="146">
          <content>The parents or caregivers eventually admit their appreciation of the mutual support working on behalf of their oppositional students.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="147">
          <content>Kids want to know they are valued.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="148">
          <content>I'm a pro at the Mr. Rogers-style handling of disruptions; however, they are ineffective when it comes to kids who are used to getting their grade just for showing up and turning something in.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="149">
          <content>There is a spectrum of student behaviors and abilities, and each much be dealt with accordingly.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="150">
          <content>SES is much more complex, and things like love and support, not to mention good parenting are worth far more than income.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="151">
          <content>Often, a student merely needs love, support, respect, and more scaffolding to get over the adolescent hump and into the makings of a mature adulthood.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="152">
          <content>Usually, poor schools simply lack the resources to properly assess, diagnose and make proper interventions.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="153">
          <content>Parents need to know what teachers are doing that works best for their child at school and teachers need to know what's working well at home.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="154">
          <content>The rudeness and disruptiveness of students who do NOT want to learn is vicious, deliberate, and, unfortunately, student coordinated when adminstrators refuse to back teachers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="155">
          <content>In most cases that would let the student know that I was aware of the behavior and not accepting of it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="156">
          <content>If that didn't work, my next step was to quietly approach the student, kneel down next to him/her and without any anger or alarm in my voice quietly ask the student "Can you behave?"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="157">
          <content>In all the years that I used this technique there were but a handful of episodes where I was unsuccessful at getting the student back on task and acting appropriately for the duration of the class.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="158">
          <content>I might add that a non-cofrontational approach and a low voice that wasn't heard by other students usually allowed the student to save face and return to work without having felt that I "won" and he/she "lost".</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="159">
          <content>A teacher in such a situation needs to be given the proper perspective: (1) yes, the administration has created conditions in which students cannot learn, (2) yes, the administration is responsible (read: able to respond) for employing any energetic, heavy-handed behavioral intervention needed, which may involve yanking five disruptive students out of class every day for many days on end (place the burden on them, your administrator, for witnessing and dealing with the conditions they?ve created) and placing the miscreants in independent/solitary study environments elsewhere on campus, (3) yes, the administration is ultimately responsible for maximizing student time on task, and thus maximizing school test scores, and (4) no, a teacher, however talented and adept at employing ?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="160">
          <content>The best strategy is not to let things get out of hand, keeping them engaged.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0505wb-43-03701">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="161">
          <content>The thought that your child is being bullied is one of the most worrying aspects of being a dad, leaving you feeling powerless, frustrated and unable to help your child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="162">
          <content>This needn't be the case, however.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="163">
          <content>Even though, by definition, bullying is something that happens to your child when you're not there, there are ways of spotting if your child may be being bullied, and positive steps you can take to bring it to an end.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="164">
          <content>Types of bullying</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="165">
          <content>Bullying can take many different forms, the common thread being the perpetrators need to make the victim feel miserable.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="166">
          <content>It doesn't have to mean a child being physically attacked or beaten.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="167">
          <content>Physical : your child being hit, kicked pinched, any form of violence</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="168">
          <content>Verbal : name calling, sarcastic comments, cruel teasing</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="169">
          <content>Emotional : often more subtle than the above but just as upsetting.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="170">
          <content>Including ridicule, humiliation and exclusion i.e. sending a child to Coventry.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="171">
          <content>CyberBullying : using modern digital communication to send hurtful or threatening messages.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="172">
          <content>Cyberbullying may take place via the internet, on chat rooms or forums, or through text messaging.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="173">
          <content>Warning signs</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="174">
          <content>A child who is being bullied may not wish to come to you and tell you about it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="175">
          <content>Perhaps the bully has warned them not to talk, or perhaps they're buying into the playground code of not telling tales.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="176">
          <content>You can do your best to combat this by creating an atmosphere in which your child knows they can come to you and get a sympathetic and understanding reaction to their worries, but even so, you may first realise your child is being bullied by spotting the warning signs:</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="177">
          <content>child is frightened of walking to and from school, perhaps changing their route or begging you to drive them in</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="178">
          <content>regularly complains of feeling ill in the mornings, starts missing school or suffers a decline in schoolwork</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="179">
          <content>broken or missing possessions</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="180">
          <content>a change in sleeping patterns, with trouble sleeping or perhaps bedwetting</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="181">
          <content>becoming withdrawn</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="182">
          <content>asks for money or perhaps even takes money (the bully may be stealing from them)</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="183">
          <content>becomes more agressive than usual, perhaps even bullying other children or younger siblings</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="184">
          <content>How to react</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="185">
          <content>If you're worried that your child is being bullied then talk to them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="186">
          <content>They may be reluctant to admit that the bullying is taking place.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="187">
          <content>Reassure them that you will not react to hastily, that you'll stay calm and not do anything to escalate the situation, but that bullying, whatever form it takes, is wrong, is not something they have to put up with, and working together you can tackle it and stop it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="188">
          <content>Listen to their fears.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="189">
          <content>Make sure they know it's not their fault and they're not alone.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="190">
          <content>Don't put pressure on them to talk.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="191">
          <content>Don't overreact.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="192">
          <content>Your first, understandable, instinct will be to grab the bully by the scruff of the neck.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="193">
          <content>The thought of you acting like this will terrify your child, so stay calm.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="194">
          <content>Simple steps</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="195">
          <content>Once you've established that bullying is taking place, there are positive steps you can take:</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="196">
          <content>if your child is being bullied at school then contact the school</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="197">
          <content>check that they have an anti-bullying policy in place.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="198">
          <content>They are required by law to do so</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="199">
          <content>arrange a meeting with the head</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="200">
          <content>make notes of the times, places and circumstances of any bullying that has taken place</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="201">
          <content>if you are not satisfied with the schools response, then write a letter of complaint to the head of the school, the chair of governors and the Local Education Authority</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="202">
          <content>keep a record of all meetings and correspondence</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="203">
          <content>ensure that the school takes action, maintaining contact and pressure until you are satisfied</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="204">
          <content>On a more general note, help your child to practice strategies for dealing with bullies, such as shouting "No!"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="205">
          <content>, walking or running away, meet with other parents to discuss the problem - they may be suffering similarly and a united front can make things easier to tackle</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="206">
          <content>Self Defence Classes - Not merely teaching your child to fight back.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="207">
          <content>self defence classes often boost a child's confidence, making bullying less likely</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0501wb-99-33588">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="208">
          <content>Understand that it is okay to express anger.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="209">
          <content>Attack the problem, not the person.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="210">
          <content>Recognize that dealing with conflict is not about winning or losing, but about behaving in the right way."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="211">
          <content>Work together on problem resolution.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="212">
          <content>Communicate your anger management and problem-solving skills with your children.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="213">
          <content>Share specifics of how you've dealt with anger.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1209wb-70-18301">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="214">
          <content>Why Do Some Kids Dislike School?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="215">
          <content>If you don't like school, the first step is finding out why.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="216">
          <content>First, write down everything you don't like about school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="217">
          <content>Then make a list of the good things you enjoy (even if it's only recess and lunch, that's a start!)</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="218">
          <content>Now, what can you change on the "don't like" list?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="219">
          <content>When you stop to think about why you don't like school, you can start taking steps to make things better.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="220">
          <content>It's a good idea to talk to someone about your problems with school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="221">
          <content>Your mom, dad, relative, teacher, or school counselor will be able to help you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="222">
          <content>It's especially important to tell an adult if the problem is that you're being bullied or someone hurts you physically.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="223">
          <content>Another good idea is to write down your feelings about school in a journal.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="224">
          <content>You can use a journal or diary or just write in an ordinary notebook.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="225">
          <content>It's a great way to let out emotions that may be stuck inside you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="226">
          <content>If you feel disorganized or like you can't keep up with your schoolwork, your teachers and school counselors want to help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="227">
          <content>Teachers want and expect you to ask for help learning stuff.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="228">
          <content>If all of your subjects seem really hard, a school counselor can help you sort things out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="229">
          <content>Special help with schoolwork is available if you need it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="230">
          <content>Try not to let the problems go on too long.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="231">
          <content>It's easier to catch up on one chapter than the whole book!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="232">
          <content>The next time you find yourself disliking school, try this:</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="233">
          <content>Would remembering to do your homework help you feel more confident if you're called on in class?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="234">
          <content>Can you get help with schoolwork that's hard?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="235">
          <content>Who can you talk to about a worry or problem you're dealing with?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="236">
          <content>Could you find a way to show off your special interests and talents?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="237">
          <content>If you made just one new friend, would you feel less alone?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="238">
          <content>If you helped someone else feel less alone, would you feel even better?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="239">
          <content>Which activities could you try that would help you meet new friends?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="240">
          <content>Of course, you might not be able to change everything on your "don't like" list.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="241">
          <content>Focus on what you can change and you might be able to put the cool back in school!</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0007wb-09-28233">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="242">
          <content>Talk to an adult you trust, such as a parent, guidance counselor, or both.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="243">
          <content>Give it time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="244">
          <content>You may not feel immediately comfortable with your teacher, but that may change as you get to know one another.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="245">
          <content>If you've given it time, talk with your parents about what to do next.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="246">
          <content>Lots of times, a meeting can be set up to discuss the problem.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1403wb-29-13381">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="247">
          <content>The stress of dealing with bullies can make kids feel sick.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="248">
          <content>Some bullies are looking for attention.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="249">
          <content>When they pick on someone else, it can make them feel big and powerful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="250">
          <content>Some bullies are copying what they've seen someone else do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="251">
          <content>Some have been bullied themselves.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="252">
          <content>Bullying: How to Handle It</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="253">
          <content>Don't give the bully a chance.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="254">
          <content>Feel good about you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="255">
          <content>Get a buddy (and be a buddy).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="256">
          <content>Fighting back just satisfies a bully and it's dangerous, too, because someone could get hurt.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="257">
          <content>Plan ahead.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0009wb-22-31017">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="258">
          <content>Dealing with difficult kids</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="259">
          <content>Even if you love your students and are great at your job, a classroom full of the school's problem kids is not easy for any teacher.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="260">
          <content>I discovered an interesting approach to the problem when I was teaching.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="261">
          <content>My theory was this: in a classroom of low-achieving students, the student's behavior would be rewarded.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="262">
          <content>The kids would likely egg him on.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="263">
          <content>In the honors class, the kids would not encourage him.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="264">
          <content>They would help keep him in line.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="265">
          <content>And, while he might not be working at the same level as the other students, he would likely learn more than he would in a class where his time was spent acting out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="266">
          <content>He tried, at least some of the time, which was a great improvement over the past.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="267">
          <content>A difficult student in an honors or gifted class always proved much more manageable than a difficult student in a "regular" class or a class of low achievers.</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0311wb-39-15354">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="268">
          <content>The counselor also wants to help you learn as much as you can in class, be a contributing member of the school community, and be a positive influence on your environment.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="269">
          <content>The counselor will try to help you figure out what's going on.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="270">
          <content>Your appointment with the counselor could happen during the day when classmates might notice you're gone.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0305wb-38-09316">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="271">
          <content>I was not a skipper, which I am actually very grateful for, even though 7th grade was the worst year of the bullying, because I have always been one of the three most-young students in my class, before the skippies at Uni.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="272">
          <content>Demanding social skills from 11 year olds is not exactly reasonable.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="273">
          <content>Most people remember their social experiences from high school more than their calculus final or their history paper.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="274">
          <content>Shouldn't one goal of any high school, including Uni, be to *help* students develop socially?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="275">
          <content>If Uni turns down a student who is lacking in so-called common sense, that child will surely face more trouble in public high schools.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="276">
          <content>Why should Uni discriminate against people based on their ability to communicate?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="277">
          <content>Communication can be taught just as well as any other subject; its as if you're suggesting to exclude all applicants who score low on math exams.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="278">
          <content>Boy, what a nasty wake-up call by the world.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="279">
          <content>Looking back, even though middle school was the worst part of my short life, I was not ready for high school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="280">
          <content>to stay at Urbana Middle School would have probably been bad because i wasnt ever challenged, and not fun at all comapred to Uni.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="281">
          <content>some people started out life too mature (okay just really mature for their age) and over time got more immature to fit with their age group.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="282">
          <content>I bet that within each class, if you just look at how each student performs behaviorally and academically, you wouldn't be able to tell who skipped a grade and who didn't.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="283">
          <content>I skipped a grade when I came to Uni and I don't feel that I would be any more prepared had I come a year later.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="284">
          <content>"No student is going to lose anything by not skipping a year, by completing seventh grade in a regular middle school."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="285">
          <content>Had I skipped a year, I would have been one of the youngest people in that class (July 91).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="286">
          <content>Our point of writing the editorial was to question the usefulness of having students skip a grade.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="287">
          <content>We just believe that developmentally, it would be beneficial for most students to not skip a grade.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="288">
          <content>Also, bear in mind that Lizzy did skip, and Lauren and I didn't, but we all share the opinions expressed in the editorial.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="289">
          <content>Statement 1: Are students who skip a grade expected to grow up too fast?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="290">
          <content>Response 2: The professors on campus who hire students of mine to work during the summer report better reliability and work performance from those who've skipped a grade, and are more likely to hire those students again than their older counterparts.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="291">
          <content>Statement 5: No student is going to lose anything by not skipping a year, by completing seventh grade in a regular middle school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="292">
          <content>Based on our own observations, parents of students who skipped a grade tend to be the ones who most fit this description.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="293">
          <content>Without considering the input of my parents, I made the decision to skip.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="294">
          <content>Skipped</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="295">
          <content>Certainly, I would not advise just anybody to skip.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="296">
          <content>It is imperative that students who skip are mature if they wish to flourish.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="297">
          <content>Fundamentally, students who skip must be socially mature.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="298">
          <content>Secondly, they must be the ones to make the decision.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="299">
          <content>Lastly, they must be able to handle the workload and maintain their competitive status in a class of significantly older students.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="300">
          <content>After graduating last year, I'm currently taking transitional (or "gap") year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="301">
          <content>I spent the summer relaxing and the fall traveling abroad while simultaneously completing volunteer hours and an internship.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="302">
          <content>In the winter, I applied to colleges.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="303">
          <content>I plan on spending the spring raising money for college and writing a book.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="304">
          <content>I also hope to continue to grow as a person and become secure in my future plans.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="305">
          <content>Most of these opportunities would have been impossible had I not skipped.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="306">
          <content>Concerning what I read of this article, I think the article's main fault is its generalities.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="307">
          <content>The choice to skip or not should be made according to the development of the person.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="308">
          <content>There are 18 -year-old graduates with the maturity of a five-year-old and there are 16-year-old graduates with the maturity of someone twice their age.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="309">
          <content>Eighteen is, by no means, the cutoff age for childhood nor is it the guaranteed age for intellectual or social maturity.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="310">
          <content>Adolescents develop at all different ages.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="311">
          <content>Certainly not all parents of children who skipped are overly protective, pushy, or restrictive.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="312">
          <content>My parents were supportive of my decision without treating me any different than if I hadn't skipped.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="313">
          <content>The majority of parents just want what is best for their child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="314">
          <content>Sometimes a non-conventional education is best.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="315">
          <content>I really have no clue how this age gap effects Uni students, but I assume they have an easier time than I did being that they are the minority instead of the exception.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="316">
          <content>Based on my experiences, the only non-successful students I know who have skipped are those that did not give skipping enough consideration.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="317">
          <content>Conversely, the majority of students I know who have skipped are more mature and stable than their older counterparts.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="318">
          <content>This is probably due to the fact that they had to work slightly harder not to fall behind.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="319">
          <content>As a future Journalism major, I want to randomly mention my amazement at the quality of the Gargoyle as a whole, its articles, and the mature debates that take place within its comments section.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="320">
          <content>I agree with Mr. Stone in that the skipping situation tends to be more complicated than is shown in this article, and the projected solution is an intriguing idea but essentially flawed.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="321">
          <content>I'd especially like to highlight that a 7th grade year can be worse than going to Uni early.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="322">
          <content>This is definitely what I thought when applying: Mahomet schools left me socially starved and educationally bored, not the ideal situation for a fragile 11-year old.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="323">
          <content>For this reason, I can't fully regret leaving Mahomet at that point.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="324">
          <content>However, not having my liscence until Senior year and graduating at the age of 16 are two aspects I'm not looking forward to, and reflecting on Subbie year, I was unfortunately particularly immature.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="325">
          <content>So faced with these observations, I would propose, not a weeding out of younger students, but an enforcement of the awareness that there IS a down-side to skipping a year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="326">
          <content>The idea that skipping is sometimes also the best idea socially is defiantly true.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="327">
          <content>I moved here from Pittsburgh after my sixth year, and if I had started at Urbana Middle School I would have had a much harder time making friends.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="328">
          <content>Because I came into this school at the same time everyone else in my grade did, I was able to focus more on studies (Not that subfreshmen year was hard or anything...).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="329">
          <content>I agree that skipping does create some problems.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="330">
          <content>However, both Mr. Stone and Andrew presented excellent reasons to keep grade skipping as an option.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="331">
          <content>I don't think interviews should be introduced into the admissions process.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="332">
          <content>I can't remember if there were questions on the teacher reference forms about maturity and behavior, but maybe these issues can be addressed more directly in the forms that teachers are asked to fill out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="333">
          <content>The admissions committee already takes some care to consider this issue, but maybe it should be given even more emphasis.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="334">
          <content>I would like to add that it's not always the youngest students who are the most immature!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="335">
          <content>The real problem is simply that the local middle schools are so terrible.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="336">
          <content>If so many kids didn't feel the need to escape, then skipping would be rare.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="337">
          <content>Ideally, I would prefer that the subbie year be discontinued, and the class size for grades 9-12 increased.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="338">
          <content>There are too many qualified students who are not accepted.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="339">
          <content>But as long as so many bright students are miserable in middle school, the subbie year should remain and skipping should be an option.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="340">
          <content>My congratulations to the Gargoyle editorial staff for tackling another complex issue.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="341">
          <content>But I think it is important that we all realize that the issues of skipping are hardly new.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="342">
          <content>"Skipping," or ending up a year ahead of one's peers in school, has been going on for decades, and is not inherently the problem.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="343">
          <content>His mother was given the choice of letting him go to kindergarten or first grade.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="344">
          <content>For our daughter, if she makes it in, we hope she will have the opportunity to be a part of a school where being an intelligent female is not a liability socially, and a place were her musical abilities and interests can be nurtured.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="345">
          <content>The issue of being "dispositionally suited" for an academic program is one we also face at the college level.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="346">
          <content>As my colleague Mr. Stone has noted, though, you have made some rather broad generalities and have not necessarily done all your homework.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="347">
          <content>Academic research rather overwhelmingly supports skipping for academic reasons as more beneficial than remaining for social/maturity reasons.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="348">
          <content>Check the academic research, not just your personal opinion/observation.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="349">
          <content>The grinding issue is not ignored in "public" schools.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="350">
          <content>Again, do some research.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="351">
          <content>Much of the issue at Uni, I would note, had less to do with the Subbies than with the fact no faculty wanted to chaperon dances with grinding.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="352">
          <content>No chaperons = no dance, right?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="353">
          <content>Jason He -- for whom I have infinite respect -- is wrong when he suggests the admission is split 50/50 by grade level.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="354">
          <content>It is split 50/50 by gender.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="355">
          <content>And having been on the committee, I can verify that much thought goes into the maturity level of the student.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="356">
          <content>Any indication on teacher recs to the contrary is an immediate and important red flag.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="357">
          <content>Interviews, which have been discussed recently, bring up multiple issues with the name-blind admission process, an important -- and often overlooked -- part of the admission process.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="358">
          <content>I know Uni isn't seen to be a social school but I think skipping a grade can really hurt future social skills.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="359">
          <content>I didn't skip, and while my two years at Franklin may not have been the most academically challenging they opened me up to numerous cultures and issues, and I had a lot of fun.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1014wb-22-07764">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="360">
          <content>Yell, attention to troublemakers, intimidation, ridicule, or the opposite-a pushover.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="361">
          <content>The other thing I have observed and my kids have observed even more is that many teachers show little to no tolerance in the classroom towards kids with special needs.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="362">
          <content>This is then handed down to the other kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="363">
          <content>What kids will show compassion and caring towards kids that the teacher gets angry with, shows contempt towards and sometimes even ridicules in front of the classroom.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1403wb-22-27944">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="364">
          <content>We're going to take a walk and get lunch instead.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="365">
          <content>As you grow older, you'll be faced with some challenging decisions.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1200tw-62-20900">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="366">
          <content>In this series, I have had the privilege of interviewing other homeschoolers from across the country.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="367">
          <content>Here to tell us how her family got started homeschooling and what her family's homeschool style looks like is Rachel.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="368">
          <content>They homeschool using a virtual school, a cyber school where the kids' learning takes place online.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="369">
          <content>How long have you been homeschooling?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="370">
          <content>We started homeschooling our older child in a very organized way when she was just 5.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="371">
          <content>Our younger child was 3 and a half at the time, and we homeschooled her in a more laid-back way (a lot of sitting in on sis's lessons, lot's of reading, some math DVD's that first year).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="372">
          <content>We are completing our second year now - and this year both kids have a very organized style of schooling.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="373">
          <content>How/why did you get started homeschooling?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="374">
          <content>The bricks and mortar public school is excellent, and they very much wanted to help and accommodate...but were clearly unable to.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="375">
          <content>Private schools were unable to deal with their special needs either.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="376">
          <content>They offered to try, everyone was nice, but everyone was honest too.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="377">
          <content>We stumbled across virtual schooling on the internet!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="378">
          <content>It is a VERY tech-y and early computer use program, which is in line with our parenting style.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="379">
          <content>I also like that we get report cards, progress reports, and the school keeps up with IEPs.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="380">
          <content>The school also welcomes lots of parental input on IEPs, and all of it can be done over the phone in a conference call, which is very freeing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="381">
          <content>For someone just coming out of public school would he or she expect to go straight into their same grade in the virtual school or are the students placed in the appropriate level for each subject they take?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="382">
          <content>They will assess for another skip this next fall (after she starts as a 3rd grader) to 4th grade, as she has completed half of her 3rd grade courses, and by fall she will have completed all of her 3rd grade work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="383">
          <content>AND classes can be radically higher in one subject and lower in another (to accommodate a strong reader who struggles with math, or vice versa).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="384">
          <content>AND they will skip a child once per year as needed.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="385">
          <content>In the lower grades, "as needed" is proved by finishing the year's work by early spring or earlier.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="386">
          <content>Entered as a kindergartener, assigned 1st grade work across the board, finished that in late winter, now in 2nd grade work, and was skipped a grade halfway through the year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="387">
          <content>However, all that said, for children in upper grades, grade placement depends on more extensive testing, and children may be officially skipped (or possibly demoted to a more appropriate lower grade) as determined.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="388">
          <content>I don't know a lot about that, I just know it's different from the early grade levels.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="389">
          <content>The flexibility with grade skipping and grade level work being done is the biggest plus with this program in my opinion.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="390">
          <content>She sends stickers, notes, and bookmarks in the mail sometimes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="391">
          <content>I would say they communicate with her about twice a month, not counting class connects.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="392">
          <content>Do your kids have interaction with other kids in the program or just with the teacher like you talked about above?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="393">
          <content>My kids' main contacts with other kids in the program is in the online guided class sessions called "class connects."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="394">
          <content>Class connects are every couple of weeks for history.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="395">
          <content>Those taper off near the end of the year as more students are either preparing for yearly testing (there are class connects for those too) or catching up on subjects they've gotten behind in.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="396">
          <content>The virtual school does field trips quite often.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="397">
          <content>Since my kids are young and VERY active, we skip long drives whenever possible.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="398">
          <content>So your kids have virtual connections... how much interaction do your kids have with other homeschoolers in your area?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="399">
          <content>I would say half of their friends are homeschooled and half are in standard schools.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="400">
          <content>Our virtual school is actually a public school by law in our state, so our only cost is $500 per child to attend school out of county.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="401">
          <content>She has one subject now that she can more or less do independently, without me constantly hovering!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="402">
          <content>I offer some choices, but they are choices like "would you like to do history and science today or would you like to do two history lessons today and two science lessons tomorrow?"</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0111wb-56-33537">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="403">
          <content>Short and sweet should be the punishment, not for long periods but I also like the 'making amends' idea like an apology and letter if needed.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="404">
          <content>Make sure that your child is capable of doing the class work he is being asked to do, for example.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="405">
          <content>Being behind (or ahead of) the class can create boredom, frustration, and anxiety-which may lead some kids to act out verbally or physically.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="406">
          <content>Understand that in this case, giving consequences is far less important than figuring out what your child needs to do differently the next time he wants to act out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="407">
          <content>In other words, if you say, "You have to stay in your room because you acted out in school today," you're not addressing the behavior and it will not help your child because you're not teaching him anything-except how to do time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="408">
          <content>Sometimes parents assume that their kids will figure out things on their own, but if you're dealing with a chronic issue, you have to face facts: your child has not figured it out by himself and he is not likely to do so.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="409">
          <content>Be realistic in your goals: When you structure your child's study time to help him bring his grades back to an acceptable level, be realistic in your goals.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="410">
          <content>On the Support Line, I've found that when parents really make a consistent effort to keep up with their kids, they are seldom caught unawares when it comes to dropping grades or poor school performance.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="411">
          <content>It's no secret that failing to attend school can lead your child or teen to become involved in risky behaviors, especially if he is not supervised consistently at home.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="412">
          <content>If your child skips school chronically, you may have to involve community services and ask them to address the underlying reasons for school truancy.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="413">
          <content>Problems at School?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="414">
          <content>How to Handle the Top 4 Issues</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="415">
          <content>Acting out in school</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="416">
          <content>When your child acts out in school , it can be worrisome, frustrating and embarrassing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="417">
          <content>On top of the actual misbehavior, you fear that he'll make a bad name for himself-that his reputation as a troublemaker will follow him from grade to grade.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="418">
          <content>You may also feel judged-and blamed-by teachers and other parents for what your child does at school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="419">
          <content>Some kids act out when they're feeling left out or left behind.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="420">
          <content>I want to stress that for the most part, you should not give consequences for school misbehavior at home, unless your child is damaging school property or hurting others physically.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="421">
          <content>That's because punishing your child at home is not going to give him the skills he needs to behave more appropriately.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="422">
          <content>In some cases, letting the school hold your child accountable is enough, but in chronic or severe acting-out situations, it will be important to work with the school to get of what is going on.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="423">
          <content>You may then need to work with some local supports to address the behavior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="424">
          <content>But for the most part, leave discipline for acting out at school to school officials-don't punish your child twice.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="425">
          <content>You need to help him.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="426">
          <content>So talk to the teacher-that's your best first step.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="427">
          <content>Take it from there.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="428">
          <content>You need a sense of why he's acting out and what's happening in order to know how you can help your child change.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="429">
          <content>And pay close attention to what your child is saying at home; he should know that all experiences are okay to share.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="430">
          <content>A word of caution: One important lesson James Lehman teaches us is to support the school authorities in front of your child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="431">
          <content>If your child hears your criticism of school officials and his teachers, he is likely to be disrespectful to them in class-and also to you, later on down the line.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="432">
          <content>If your child's grades are dropping, rule number one is to become an investigator.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="433">
          <content>In other words, really find out what's going on with your child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="434">
          <content>Is he having problems at home or with other kids at school?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="435">
          <content>Is he having a tough time adjusting to middle school or high school?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="436">
          <content>Are his study habits poor-and can you work on that together?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="437">
          <content>For some kids, learning disabilities and medical problems may play a role.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="438">
          <content>And for still others, drug and alcohol use may be the cause of falling grades.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="439">
          <content>The main thing for you to do is find out the "why" and then come up with a plan to help your child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="440">
          <content>Here are some steps you can take immediately:</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="441">
          <content>Meet with your child's teacher: Call your child's teacher and ask for a meeting.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="442">
          <content>Tell her what you are seeing at home-and then ask what she has observed in the classroom.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="443">
          <content>Ask her for any ideas she might have to help your child get back on track.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="444">
          <content>Set up more structure at home.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="445">
          <content>A common problem for many kids is a lack of structure in their after school schedule.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="446">
          <content>Make sure sports or other clubs do not come first, with homework being fit in at the end of the day (when your child is exhausted).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="447">
          <content>This is not a good lesson to teach your child because it gives them the message that play comes before work-and is therefore more important than work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="448">
          <content>Clubs or sports should not come before school work and family time for your child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="449">
          <content>The bottom line is that schoolwork has to be prioritized, and a structure has to be set up so it isn't squeezed in at the last minute.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="450">
          <content>Remember, it took time for your child to get behind, so you need to allow time for him to catch up.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="451">
          <content>Get actively involved in your child's homework by reviewing it and helping with study strategies.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="452">
          <content>I also recommend that you try to be present during study time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="453">
          <content>I know that many parents work and can't be at home with their children after school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="454">
          <content>If you or your spouse can't be there, try to get your child into in an after school program or ask another trusted adult to be there with them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="455">
          <content>Don't restrict your child from privileges until his grades improve.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="456">
          <content>Understand that restricting your child from all of his privileges until he brings his grades up usually backfires.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="457">
          <content>In effect, you end up taking away something that might actually motivate your child to improve.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="458">
          <content>Instead, I recommend that you require your child to study for a certain amount of time each day to earn those extras that night.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="459">
          <content>Talk to your child about what's going on.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="460">
          <content>Have a frank conversation with your child about his grades.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="461">
          <content>Say, "Look, I've been letting you manage your homework on your own, but it's not working.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="462">
          <content>Now we're going to set up a study time every day where I supervise your work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="463">
          <content>We can talk about not doing that once your grades get back up where they need to belong.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="464">
          <content>But in the meantime, we have to seriously set aside some time to work on this."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="465">
          <content>And remember to ask your child about his day and show that you are interested; ask questions that require a longer answer than "yes" or "no."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="466">
          <content>If your child is skipping school-either playing sick or skipping out of classes-again, you first need to investigate and find out why.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="467">
          <content>Is your child failing, being bullied, under the influence of alcohol or drugs, or does he have physical problems?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="468">
          <content>Some kids develop anxiety around going to school; they can have stomach aches or headaches as a result.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="469">
          <content>A lot of kids will say they're sick in order to avoid school because they have anxiety about it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="470">
          <content>If there's an anxiety issue at play, a visit to your child's pediatrician to determine whether counseling is in order might be your best course of action.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="471">
          <content>A skilled counselor can gently get your child over the hump and teach them ways of coping with their nervousness around school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="472">
          <content>So the reason why your child is missing school chronically needs to be understood so it can be resolved.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="473">
          <content>For example, if your child is being bullied , you will need to work with the school to make sure your child is protected and that it stops.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="474">
          <content>The juvenile justice system does not like the idea of kids skipping school and loitering around town, so there may be hope there.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="475">
          <content>You might call up your local police department and say, "I can't get my child to go to school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="476">
          <content>Are there any resources available in this community to help me get him back on track?"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="477">
          <content>Understand that if your child is chronically skipping school, it's usually the result of a problem that has built up for quite some time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="478">
          <content>Often it's the end of a long string of problems, rather than the beginning.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="479">
          <content>For this reason, I believe this is an issue that's important to nip in the bud at an early stage.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="480">
          <content>So when your child's grades start dropping or he's coming home moody and sad, intervene then.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="481">
          <content>Keep the communication open and always stay interested in what's happened to your child from day to day-it will pay off in the end, I promise you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="482">
          <content>Discussions don't work, encouragement/rewards don't work, withholding of privileges doesn't work, and they don't have conflicts with ohter commitments.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="483">
          <content>I have to agree with some of these comments about still punishing at home for school consequences.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="484">
          <content>Only being driven by consequences and threatening.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="485">
          <content>As both parent and teacher, I agree with one of the main points, that of finding out what the main problem is behind the negative behaviors, but I disagree that there should be no further consequence at home for poor choices kids make at school.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1912wb-97-14103">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="486">
          <content>Don't get me wrong, teaching is an incredibly reflective practice, but sometimes (especially when I'm working with particular types of groups that spend their time away from school doing god knows what), I've found it easier to leave thinking about it in my class.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="487">
          <content>Once they verbalize whatever's getting their goat, they're usually good to go.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0401wb-65-21476">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="488">
          <content>Others may be pressured to take risks like steal, pull pranks, or bully other kids in order to stay in the clique.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0502wb-90-15758">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="489">
          <content>Perhaps the most important thing that helped me get through these years was support, which I found in both books and people.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="490">
          <content>Raising Your Spirited Child: A Guide for Parents Whose Child is More Intense, Sensitive, Perceptive, Persistent, Energetic</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="491">
          <content>Kids, Parents and Power Struggles: Winning for a Lifetime .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="492">
          <content>The Difficult Child , by Stanley Turecki with Leslie Tonner</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="493">
          <content>While the written word can provide a lot of information, there is no substitute for an understanding ear, especially if you are fortunate, as I was, to find someone who has specific insight into dealing with a "hard" child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="494">
          <content>Another key I learned in dealing with my child was acceptance.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="495">
          <content>My child was and is more difficult than average; in fact, he was so far at one end of the spectrum that his father and I at times considered the possibility that he was beyond "normal," and that we may need professional help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="496">
          <content>In any case, we believed that informed, careful and determined parenting was his best hope for helping him learn to get along in the world.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="497">
          <content>(If you don't have a way to develop resources to deal with this kind of child, or if your child appears "over the edge" to you, getting professional help may be called for.)</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="498">
          <content>If you are dealing with a difficult child and you haven't seriously considered how diet, sleep and television are affecting your child, I encourage you to examine how adjusting diet, helping to insure the most rest possible, and limiting or foregoing "screen time" might improve things for your family.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="499">
          <content>Additionally, while Tom had a difficult time going to sleep, was a poor napper, and did not "sleep through the night" until he was five, we still kept up our warm bedtime routine and started plenty early so that even if it took him a long time to go to sleep, he would be well rested the next day.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="500">
          <content>Like we did, you may find that the actual medium of television, not just its content, is something that is best avoided or limited with difficult kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="501">
          <content>This may help with a parent's acceptance of how "different" the child seems from her childhood self.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="502">
          <content>i am a single mum of a six year old boy, and i need help as i do not know what to do anymore, his got a very bad temper, he reply me and his teachers at school.He beats up kids at school, and that scares me, cause not every parent is the same.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="503">
          <content>He disturbs the class and does not do his work, and his very bright...am scared sometimes to pick him up from school as i think he did something bad.I talk to him everyday before school, but nothing seem to change...please help!!!!!!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="504">
          <content>These books helped to reframe a child's negative qualities as positive ones (a "stubborn" child may be thought of as "determined," an "inflexible" child has "focus"), and they offered specific strategies for dealing with intense children.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="505">
          <content>Well-meaning acquaintances or relatives, and even some professionals, can have a toxic effect when they are dismissive of our concerns or offer simplistic solutions: "I'd just spank him until he knows who's boss" or "My children wouldn't dare do that!"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="506">
          <content>While dealing with a demanding child seems to leave no energy for anything else, it has been absolutely worth the effort to seek a supportive mentor or group to help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="507">
          <content>It was easy enough to keep a jug of water, fruit and bread in the car.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="508">
          <content>We found that very little to no television was our best bet in helping him manage as a two- and three-year-old.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0005wb-17-05223">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="509">
          <content>I also highly recommend you signing up for a class called Parent Project.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1701wb-23-24841">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="510">
          <content>Teacher had mentioned in passing early in the year that maybe they should be split up.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="511">
          <content>2 weeks ago, other mom had a meeting with principal because of a few more incidents and he agreed to switch her son to a different class.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="512">
          <content>The principal, teacher and another teacher all made a point of saying to me that G did nothing wrong and that this boy was not really being very nice to him.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="513">
          <content>Not a good excuse for that kind of behavior....especially in adults but sometimes we're so overwhelmed that it comes out like that.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1811wb-60-13509">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="514">
          <content>Trails wants those kids who are lost in the middle, the ones not previously identified as either the problems or the superstars.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="515">
          <content>Those invisible kids are the ones that need Trails for they are the ones in danger of falling through the cracks."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="516">
          <content>Kathleen Milligan is a Master Practitioner of NLP and a member of the NLP Canada Training Advisory Board.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="517">
          <content>Her practice includes children who have yet to be born (she works with fertility clients and moms-to-be) and many more who have hit bumpy spots and been referred to her by schools, doctors or other practitioners.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="518">
          <content>She combines hypnosis, NLP, EFT and energy psychology in a unique blending that helps children connect with their strengths and with the people around them.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1314wb-22-03705">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="519">
          <content>Allow each child to enter your room with a clean slate.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="520">
          <content>Give them an opportunity to re-invent themselves.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="521">
          <content>Let them start over.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="522">
          <content>This school year, as you attempt to change kids' behaviors and attitudes, you'll do well to remember the concept of successive approximations.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="523">
          <content>This concept holds that behavior and attitudes will change gradually and slowly.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="524">
          <content>Progress will often be plodding.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="525">
          <content>But you must recognize and reinforce each step toward the target behavior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="526">
          <content>But, on a day when she only interrupts six times, you must praise and reinforce her effort and progress.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="527">
          <content>But you must reinforce him every time he canters, trots, or skips.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="528">
          <content>You cannot wait until he walks appropriately before praising him.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="529">
          <content>You must reinforce each bit of progress and effort, or the progress and effort will stop!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="530">
          <content>Every one of your students is somebody's child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="531">
          <content>Give them the dignity and respect that you would want for your own kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="532">
          <content>Read the kids' files and seriously consider the input and opinions of the teachers who worked with the child in the past.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="533">
          <content>Who is to say that the English teacher might not have a great idea about how to get the kid to show up on time for his math class?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="534">
          <content>Therefore, the poor speller disrupts the spelling bee; the kid with verbal difficulties acts up during class discussions; the student with math difficulties gets thrown out of his algebra class.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1314wb-63-28760">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="535">
          <content>R - Reward direction, not perfection</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="536">
          <content>This school year, as you attempt to change kids&#65533; behaviors and attitudes, you'll do well to remember the concept of successive approximations.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="537">
          <content>Remember : Hurt people hurt people.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="538">
          <content>Don&#65533;t take it personally.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="539">
          <content>In a few weeks, twenty-five sets of parents will be entrusting you with their most precious possession &#65533; their child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="540">
          <content>They are not dropping off their air conditioner or their lawn mower for repair, they are giving over the care of their baby.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="541">
          <content>You must view this trust as a sacred and humbling responsibility.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="542">
          <content>Quite simply, there is no greater privilege or responsibility that one human being can give to another than to surrender temporary care of their child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="543">
          <content>Take this responsibility seriously.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="544">
          <content>But, it is realistic to expect you to treat your students with the same respect and sensitivity that you would hope that your kids&#65533; teachers would give to them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="545">
          <content>Every one of your students is somebody&#65533;s child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="546">
          <content>You would hope that the teacher would stop and provide your child with the care and comfort that s/he needs.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="547">
          <content>So do it for somebody else&#65533;s kid.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="548">
          <content>Parents surrender their child to you with the expectation of in loco parentis .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="549">
          <content>You are the parent in the parent&#65533;s absence.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="550">
          <content>We need to drastically modify our approach and adopt a transdisciplinary model to our teams.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="551">
          <content>When twelve highly trained professionals and the child&#65533;s parents sit around a table, you have a virtual treasure chest of wisdom, training, and experience present.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="552">
          <content>Transdisciplinary meetings allow the team members to "take their uniforms off."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="553">
          <content>They are no longer at the meeting to defend, represent, and protect their departments - they are there to defend, represent, and protect the student .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="554">
          <content>I promise you will find that transdisciplinary meetings are lively, stimulating, productive - and effective.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="555">
          <content>We discuss important issues and solve real problems.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="556">
          <content>Solutions are based upon the child&#65533;s best interests, not on the needs of the adults.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="557">
          <content>I never feel more like a professional than when I sit around that table."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="558">
          <content>At any given moment, any kid would prefer to be viewed as a bad kid rather than a dumb kid.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="559">
          <content>Children, particularly adolescents, live daily in paralyzing fear of being embarrassed in front of their peers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="560">
          <content>If they are put in the position of looking bad or looking dumb , they will invariably choose to look bad .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="561">
          <content>This year, if a child is acting consistently "bad," reflect for a moment: are your approaches and activities making him look "dumb?"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="562">
          <content>If they are, he will choose to look "bad" and disrupt the activity in an attempt to prevent his weakness from being displayed for all to see.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="563">
          <content>Before you change the child&#65533;s behavior, maybe you need to change your own.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="564">
          <content>She constantly told us to try new strategies and approaches and avoid getting in a "classroom rut" when you use the same materials and methods year after year after year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="565">
          <content>Try different approaches.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="566">
          <content>Modify your methods.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="567">
          <content>Keep your teaching fresh!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="568">
          <content>Read the kids&#65533; files and seriously consider the input and opinions of the teachers who worked with the child in the past.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="569">
          <content>BUT don&#65533;t let these reports shade your opinions about (and treatment of) that child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="570">
          <content>So let&#65533;s make a commitment to deal more effectively and sensitively with these kids who struggle with learning every day through no choice or fault of their own.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="571">
          <content>These kids need a commitment in time, energy, and resources.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="572">
          <content>They don't learn, they need to be taught .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="573">
          <content>You cannot pick and choose the difficulties that you will accept or that you will reject.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="574">
          <content>You can&#65533;t say, "I understand he has difficulty reading, but I will not tolerate his continually losing his homework."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="575">
          <content>Some children require a visual approach; others need auditory methods.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="576">
          <content>Some students benefit from structured phonics; other students require a more language-based approach.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="577">
          <content>This school year, make a commitment to provide sensitive support on the kids&#65533; "bad days" and to embrace, celebrate, and maximize their "good days."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="578">
          <content>Try to be a sentry against this hopelessness.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="579">
          <content>Let your classroom be the one place where they feel safe, secure, and valued.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="580">
          <content>Demonstrate that you accept them and provide them with much needed attention and affection.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="581">
          <content>Small, unsolicited (and often undeserved) acts of kindness can do much to soften and reach the troubled child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="582">
          <content>A smile, an encouraging note, a positive comment on the top of a homework assignment, asking about his dog, greeting him at the classroom door, a hand on his shoulder, using his nickname, or sending him a postcard from your vacation can truly make a difference.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="583">
          <content>Don&#65533;t take this behavior personally.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="584">
          <content>Rather, continue to provide him support and warmth.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0112wb-19-21771">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="585">
          <content>Parents can get in big trouble when their kids skip school , sometimes even facing fines and jail time themselves.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="586">
          <content>Recently in Florida, a law was passed that states that parents can go to jail for up to two months when their children (age 16 and under) skip school repeatedly, missing more than 15 days in one three-month period.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="587">
          <content>Are parents to blame when their children skip school, or should the kids be held accountable - or does the answer lie somewhere in the middle?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="588">
          <content>A STUDENT should bear the responsibility for not going to school if they are skipping.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="589">
          <content>If a parent SENDS the child the parent should not be held accountable for the child skipping out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="590">
          <content>Unfortunately this was in November, it is now January, he has run away twice, continued using drugs and drinking, and skipping.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="591">
          <content>My son skipped school a lot during his high school years and it took him an extra year to complete his high school education.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="592">
          <content>I'm pretty sure it's the rare parent that sits back and does nothing, allowing their kid to skip school when ever they choose.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="593">
          <content>My son is 14 and has made a habbit of skipping (staying home from) school regularly over the past 3 years.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="594">
          <content>and how can a parent know or stop them from skipping when maybe they have work in the morn' and don't see them go to school or they assume they do stay at school when they ride the bus there</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="595">
          <content>Now in Kentucky, lawmakers have decided to turn the tables: In the town of Covington, minor students can be arrested on misdemeanor charges for playing hooky - and if their parents are complicit, they can be taken in along with their kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="596">
          <content>Officers have an option of giving kids a warning, taking them home, or booking them if the child is suspended or has been expelled, and the parents can't be reached.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="597">
          <content>It's the child who needs held accountable for their actions.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="598">
          <content>If the parent is allowing it, not sending them etc. that's another story</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="599">
          <content>What happened with my own son is he was brought before an attendance panel which in Alberta is a division of the Court of Queens Bench.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="600">
          <content>They were highly proffessional and accomodating, and believed my son could do better.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="601">
          <content>He owned up to his indiscretions, assured the board it would not continue.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="602">
          <content>The school knows me quite well and have been working with me consistantly.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="603">
          <content>We meet again before the attendance board next week and there are some other options hopefully that they can make available, I will plead on my son's behalf and offer solutions to a problem I cannot seem to fix.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="604">
          <content>Situations are different - it can be the parents fault or it can be the kids fault - it all comes down to the details - why should there be a law across the board?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="605">
          <content>Its a battle everyday - we are exhausted but were consistent with our expectations - the school has been of no help what so ever - I think if I was sent to jail for this I would end up going in for murder instead for the judge that would actually rule this in our situation.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="606">
          <content>I have a question though - if the parents went to jail - what happens with the kids?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="607">
          <content>maybe it's worth the trip!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="608">
          <content>He hated school, struggled with academics, and felt that he was a misfit.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="609">
          <content>Struggles with school led to isues with self esteem.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="610">
          <content>Since leaving school he has done much better.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="611">
          <content>His self esteem is greatly improved and he has learned through successes in life that he is not stupid.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="612">
          <content>Recently he ran in to a teacher who had labelled him lazy and incompetent and he told the teacher how he felt as a child when he was ridiculed in the classroom in front of peers for the struggles that he was having.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="613">
          <content>Recently my son wrote me a card thanking me for always believing in him and being there for him as he struggled through his teen years.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="614">
          <content>I do not support a system that would charge children and parents across the board with non attendance without addressing the issus that are keeping them away.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="615">
          <content>My experience is that many of the parents of children who struggle in school also struggled in school themselves.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="616">
          <content>I had an agreement with the school that if she missed anymore time, she was supposed to get an in school suspension, which isn't happening, and she has now run away from home and is staying with different friends.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="617">
          <content>I think that if I could have her arrested and put in "jail" for a day or two, it might just be enough to curb the behaviour and get her back on track.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="618">
          <content>Penalizing a parent that is already feeling pushed to the limits by a "difficult kid", just seems wrong.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="619">
          <content>In our case sending our son to jail for a stint might just be beneficial.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="620">
          <content>The school has been involved and helpful as much as they can, but truly, until he decides to change, nothing we do or say is going to get him there.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0006wb-39-14200">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="621">
          <content>Dealing with school</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="622">
          <content>Meet with teachers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="623">
          <content>Point out any special needs, like having to go to the bathroom frequently.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="624">
          <content>Meet with coaches and other appropriate staff, too.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="625">
          <content>Make sure the school has written health care instructions, such as medication schedules, special diet needs, your pediatrician's contact information, and emergency plans.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="626">
          <content>Encourage her to speak up .</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="627">
          <content>If she can't see something, has a question, or just needs a little extra support, the teacher is there to help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="628">
          <content>Reassure her if she needs special education classes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="629">
          <content>If a girl is moved out of a mainstream class, make sure she understands that this is done to help her learn better.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="630">
          <content>The move is not a punishment or sign there's something wrong with her.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="631">
          <content>Ask the school to provide work if she misses class.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="632">
          <content>If a child will be out for a long time, find out about special tutors or online lessons.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="633">
          <content>Ease her transition back to school after a long absence.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="634">
          <content>If she's going to have special needs after her absence or if she might look different, work with her on what she can say to classmates.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="635">
          <content>Ask her if she'd like to have the school nurse tell classmates what to expect.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="636">
          <content>Children with certain conditions may qualify for special services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA).</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="637">
          <content>An Individualized Education Program (IEP) lists the kinds of special help a student will receive.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="638">
          <content>These might include having extra time on tests, sitting in the front of the class, or special tools (called "assistive technology") like talking calculators or Braille keyboards.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="639">
          <content>To qualify for an IEP, a child needs to have an evaluation by education professionals.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="640">
          <content>Special teachers, parents or guardians, and the child all are important parts of the team that writes the IEP.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="641">
          <content>You can invite anyone who works closely with your child to participate in making the plan if you think they can help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="642">
          <content>If you think the services aren't working well, you can ask for a team meeting.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="643">
          <content>If you think a child's education rights aren't being met, you have options, including asking for an official hearing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="644">
          <content>If you think you need a lawyer, you can ask the school district about low-cost or free legal services.</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0110wb-78-00381">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="645">
          <content>Students provide only positive feedback about The City, describing it as both stimulating and fun.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="646">
          <content>"Any time you can incorporate technology into your class, they'll eat it up."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="647">
          <content>Student 1: It definitely wasn't something that you normally see in school and most of the stuff you do is pretty boring, and this was interesting and interactive.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="648">
          <content>I liked it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="649">
          <content>One of the techniques that The City uses to draw students in and make it more stimulating and engaging is they have introduced eight characters and they are at different life stages.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="650">
          <content>Any time you can incorporate technology into your class, they'll eat it up.</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1613wb-48-09130">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="651">
          <content>I don't want to do it just because it "seems cool."</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1410wb-53-11565">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="652">
          <content>Finding Help</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="653">
          <content>And you don't have to share what you've written with others.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="654">
          <content>Feeling Better About School</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1315wb-21-10784">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="655">
          <content>They are the "Saturday kids" - the kids who are confident and competent on Saturdays, summers, and school vacations, but are frightened and frustrated when they enter the classroom.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="656">
          <content>"Back to school" routines have been a part of my life for most of my Augusts as a student, a teacher, a dad, a school administrator, and now as a school consultant.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="657">
          <content>The first day of school represents something of a rebirth.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="658">
          <content>They hold tightly to the belief that "if I can't see the teacher, the teacher can't see me."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="659">
          <content>You may choose to ignore the behavior but you can't ignore the underlying need.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="660">
          <content>Teachers recognize that we must use a variety of approaches to teach reading because children learn to read in a variety of ways.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="661">
          <content>However, many teachers will attempt to motivate all thirty, unique and disparate students in the class by using one, solitary approach.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="662">
          <content>Teachers must also use a variety of motivational approaches.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="663">
          <content>There are six basic "drives" that inspire students to strive toward their fullest potential.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="664">
          <content>One of the most common - but least understood - difficulties experienced by struggling students is performance inconsistency.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="665">
          <content>This school year, make a commitment to provide sensitive support on the kids' "bad days" and to embrace, celebrate, and maximize their "good days."</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1314wb-22-03719">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="666">
          <content>Before you change the child's behavior, maybe you need to change your own.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="667">
          <content>You should also remember that September marks a "New Year" for your students, too.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="668">
          <content>Give them an opportunity for a fresh start.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="669">
          <content>Don't let difficulties or issues from last year spill over into this year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="670">
          <content>Wipe the slate clean.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="671">
          <content>BUT don't let these reports shade your opinions about (and treatment of) that child.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="672">
          <content>Let him begin the school year with a clean slate.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0311wb-72-00971">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="673">
          <content>You might not like school because a bully is bothering you, or because a kid you don't like wants to hang around with you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="674">
          <content>Maybe the work is too easy and you get bored.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="675">
          <content>Or maybe the work is too hard, or you don't feel as smart as the other kids.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0100tw-48-02004">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="676">
          <content>In Algebra II, remember to do group work, and do more " participation quizzes " during that group work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="677">
          <content>The point would be to add a more "cultural" component to the class, and a lot of my kids love reading and learning about tangents.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="678">
          <content>In Algebra II, remember to utilize the Park School of Baltimore curriculum , especially when working on Quadratics, Transformations, and Exponential Functions.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="679">
          <content>It didn't quite fit in with our 2nd quarter material, but it will align with our 3rd and 4th quarters.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="680">
          <content>In Algebra II - since we don't have a midterm for students to see a broad view and get a review of all the 1st and 2nd quarter's material - have the 3rd and 4th quarter problem sets include "review problems" from topics from the first semester.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="681">
          <content>Or if not, have review problem assignments, in addition to the problem sets.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="682">
          <content>In Calculus, continue having kids work in groups on challenging problems every so often.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="683">
          <content>Their schools work really hard to help every student succeed, but they don't have the resources that my school had to help the kids who can really do more.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1410wb-77-23150">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="684">
          <content>Sometimes, kids and grown-ups have difficult problems.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="685">
          <content>They help students handle almost any problem that could get in the way of learning, guide them to productive futures, and try to create a positive environment for everyone at school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="686">
          <content>Perhaps you just found out that your parents are getting divorced , or your dog just died, and you're so upset that you can't concentrate on doing your homework.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="687">
          <content>Counselors Help You Cope</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="688">
          <content>Today, counselors are called upon to help students in a broader way.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0911wb-78-01952">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="689">
          <content>These are all subjective, pejorative labels that attempt to describe in medical terms various states of acting or being, visible emotional turmoil or ways of perceiving the world that do not fit into the arbitrary mold of 'normalcy'.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0102wb-06-09009">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="690">
          <content>Home   |   iAssist   |   Admin 4 City Hall Plaza, Chaska, MN 55318  |   (952) 448-9395   |   Carver County Copyright 2012 by Carver County Library and JFD</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0109wb-94-24064">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="691">
          <content>Dealing With Kids' Setbacks</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="692">
          <content>Some days it just seems all too much.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="693">
          <content>You get a call from the school about an incident with your son.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="694">
          <content>Or your daughter comes home defiant and tearful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="695">
          <content>And whatever you do seems like the wrong thing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="696">
          <content>Well, it's probably not.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="697">
          <content>The right thing to do isn't always the perfect thing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="698">
          <content>Or rather, you don't need to find the perfect solution to do something that helps.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="699">
          <content>If you're like most parents (and by most parents, I mean, me) you don't routinely hit the ball out of the park.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="700">
          <content>There's a fair amount of trial and error involved.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="701">
          <content>And it's even more of a challenge as your child gets older.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="702">
          <content>We usually do too much or too little.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="703">
          <content>But it helps when you start to understand that this is the way it works.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="704">
          <content>Raising children, and especially children with special needs, is a constant state of discovering what - and how much -- to do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="705">
          <content>For one thing, you never know how much independence they can handle until you give them too much.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="706">
          <content>It's sort of like being in a sailboat.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="707">
          <content>Whatever your destination, you're constantly dealing with winds trying to blow you off course.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="708">
          <content>You often have to tack back and forth, not always able to steer exactly toward your goal, but constantly getting closer, until you reach it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="709">
          <content>Just as we can't usually sail directly to our goals, we often can't help our kids solve problems immediately.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="710">
          <content>But if we keep providing course corrections and don't get discouraged, we can help them make steady progress.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="711">
          <content>Of course, sometimes it's hard not to get discouraged.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="712">
          <content>And sometimes we're too close to an event to see the better courses of action.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="713">
          <content>So we need to be careful about making decisions affecting the future in a fury of frustration.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="714">
          <content>"We're never going to a fast food restaurant again!"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="715">
          <content>or "I'm going to call that child's mother and give her a piece of my mind!"</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="716">
          <content>Radical solutions can sometimes do more harm than good.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="717">
          <content>Better to wait and look at the problem with the perspective a little time can give, even if it's only an hour or a day.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="718">
          <content>And it always helps to step outside the problem and look at it objectively.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="719">
          <content>What caused the problem?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="720">
          <content>What can you or your child do differently?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="721">
          <content>If you need to convince your child to do something different, what incentives can you come up with?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="722">
          <content>Focus on how he can get something he wants if he takes a certain course of action.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="723">
          <content>And success is an amazing teacher.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="724">
          <content>If a child tries something and it works, she'll almost always put it in her bag of tricks.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="725">
          <content>In my experience, negative consequences tend to shut down kids' minds.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="726">
          <content>But even stubborn minds tend to seek out pleasure and the prospect of positive results.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="727">
          <content>Be careful of getting dragged down into a contest of wills.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="728">
          <content>"Because I say so," is not a convincing argument.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="729">
          <content>And kids often find creative ways around obeying ultimatums.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="730">
          <content>You've got to be the parent.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="731">
          <content>You may not be smarter than your kids (I know this first-hand), but you have more experience.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="732">
          <content>And you have a secret weapon.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="733">
          <content>You love them even when they lose control.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="734">
          <content>They may be overwhelmed by the moment and frozen in injustice or disappointment or hopelessness.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="735">
          <content>But adults tend to understand that there are few things more powerful than knowing someone cares about you and believes in you no matter what.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="736">
          <content>Just listening to their frustration or anger can help defuse it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="737">
          <content>Have you ever seen your child so upset that he didn't want anyone suggesting solutions?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="738">
          <content>You just don't UNDERSTAND!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="739">
          <content>It's an insult to suggest there was anything else he could have done!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="740">
          <content>It was just UNFAIR!</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="741">
          <content>By staying calm, you can help the storm pass.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="742">
          <content>You can be the safe haven.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="743">
          <content>You can repair the torn sails and restock the ship and supply fresh navigation charts.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="744">
          <content>And give your child the confidence to try again.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="745">
          <content>Belief is a powerful force.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="746">
          <content>If you convince your daughter she can succeed, her chances of reaching a goal go up dramatically.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="747">
          <content>Sometimes, belief is everything.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="748">
          <content>My wife has an uncle (Uncle William) who had a setback as a high school junior.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="749">
          <content>When he got his report card at the year's end, it said he'd flunked -- and would have to repeat the 11th grade.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="750">
          <content>William anxiously had a friend take the report card to his mother while he went to his after-school job delivering telegrams.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="751">
          <content>When he got home, he found his mother had fixed him his favorite dinner, fried chicken, and baked him a big apple pie.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="752">
          <content>And she didn't say a word about his report card that night.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="753">
          <content>The next day, they sat down together and came up with a plan.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="754">
          <content>In spite of being scared, William went alone to the school and negotiated an agreement that he could go on to the 12th grade with his class if he retook some key courses in summer school and passed.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="755">
          <content>He did just that.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="756">
          <content>And he went on to succeed in college and graduate school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="757">
          <content>Today, Uncle William is a respected minister and community leader.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="758">
          <content>Love and understanding can see you through the toughest times and give your kids a lifelong example to follow.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="759">
          <content>So, the next time your child has a setback, you have an opportunity.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="760">
          <content>You can understand that setbacks are not an interruption of the process, they're part of the process.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="761">
          <content>However you decide to help, it can be the right thing even if it's not the perfect thing.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="762">
          <content>And you can't go wrong with apple pie.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="763">
          <content>You can find more articles on his website at: www.coultervideo.com .</content>
        </s>
      </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0107wb-55-09096">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="764">
          <content>Accepting the situation helped me develop strategies that resulted in Tom's improvement and in the ability to get our family through the day.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="765">
          <content>For instance, while experiments with the Feingold diet did not bring about improvements for our son, many parents find children's behavior vastly better when they eliminate certain chemicals, additives and food dyes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="766">
          <content>We eat few of those anyway, and we continued to find that general good nutrition emphasizing whole foods and no caffeine did make a difference, as did paying particular attention to anticipating our son's inability to cope with hunger and thirst.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="767">
          <content>We never allowed Tom to watch such action-packed television as The Power Rangers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="768">
          <content>Finally, my experience in talking to parents of difficult toddlers and preschoolers is that a large majority of them are boys.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="769">
          <content>Mothers especially may benefit from reading and thinking about gender differences in young children.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="770">
          <content>This is a great topic to get Dad's insight on as well.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="771">
          <content>And finally, it may help you come up with creative ideas for channeling your son's energy.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="772">
          <content>Believe it or not, Tom was using a real hammer and nails at his own wooden workbench-wearing eye protection-before he turned three.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="773">
          <content>Had you ever looked into the Hand in Hand parenting technique.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="774">
          <content>They have a website and have classes that talk about techniques to help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="775">
          <content>Also they have support groups and 'listening partnerships'</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1808wb-09-23051">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="776">
          <content>A school counselor or your friends also can be helpful to you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="777">
          <content>Get organized.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="778">
          <content>What did you eat at school?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="779">
          <content>Every night before going to school or other activities, you can go over the checklist and make sure you have the snacks and medicines you'll need for the next day.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0311wb-39-15353">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="780">
          <content>But it's better for everyone if homeschooling isn't chosen just as an escape from school or problems there, such as bullying .</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1316wb-31-06674">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="781">
          <content>A great person to share your thoughts and feelings with is your school counselor.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="782">
          <content>Add school counselors to the list of people you can turn to when you need help.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="783">
          <content>Your school counselor is available for you and wants to make your school experience the best it can be.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="784">
          <content>The counselor's job is to take your problem seriously and help you find a solution.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="785">
          <content>If someone was bullying you, for instance, the counselor would talk to you about it and could give you some ideas and strategies on how to deal with the bully.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="786">
          <content>If you'd prefer not to miss class time, ask the counselor if you can talk before school, at recess, during lunch, study hall, or after school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="787">
          <content>What Else Do Counselors Do?</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0109wb-26-03283">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="788">
          <content>I'm not talking about throwing out discipline and consequences.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="789">
          <content>I'm talking about applying the rules with compassion and making accommodations while you help a child see things from a perspective that's foreign to him.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="790">
          <content>About trying to find out what a child is thinking and why she acts the way she does.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="791">
          <content>It's not enough to tell these kids the rules, because their brains are operating from a separate set of rules that seem right to them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="792">
          <content>About seeking help if dealing with a special needs child, along with other children, becomes overwhelming.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="793">
          <content>What if we live by the approach adopted by the mission control crew in the movie "Apollo 13," when three astronauts' lives were at stake?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="794">
          <content>"Failure is not an option."</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0005wb-16-22811">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="795">
          <content>If your child acts up, don't bend the rules, but understand what feelings may be motivating that behavior.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1803wb-54-13967">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="796">
          <content>What is the difference between a teacher who gets to know their kids, and one who keeps their distance?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="797">
          <content>Do you think you would treat you kids differently if they got to know you better?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="798">
          <content>Would they respond differently to you if your relationship with them was stronger?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="799">
          <content>If you had to speak to a kid how would the conversation be different if they were next to you, instead of across the classroom?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="800">
          <content>I wasn't happy with some of the kids and their work on an assignment we had just done...and I was in a blame them mood.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="801">
          <content>I rattled off a list of kids that I wanted to meet with "after class."</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="802">
          <content>At the end of the period most of the class left and those on the list remained at their seats.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="803">
          <content>Out of the bowels of my old teacher self came all sorts of threats, what are you all thinking, and this is not how you want to continue in this class sort of comments.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="804">
          <content>I felt strong afterwards for being that demanding teacher who did not let them slide.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="805">
          <content>I had won, they left defeated.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="806">
          <content>I started off the same way, I rattled off a list of names.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="807">
          <content>Proceeded with class.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="808">
          <content>Class ended, and most of the class filed out and only the kids who I named were left behind...but they were not in their seats.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="809">
          <content>Without any prompting on my part they left their seats and came up right up close and stood in front of me, and on the sides...I was nearly surrounded.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="810">
          <content>They were too close for the heavy artillery.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="811">
          <content>My heavy duty comments and yelling were long distance weapons, to be used when I was in power in the front of the room, and when they were in their seats...where they belong.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="812">
          <content>Now they were close, they had cornered me in a corner of the room in neutral territory.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="813">
          <content>This was too close for any of the heavy duty weapons in my arsenal, I had to shift to winning hearts and minds.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="814">
          <content>I spoke softly, was supportive, developed plans to assist them, and tried to give them what they needed to be successful...options that I missed the first time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="815">
          <content>There were even...smiles.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="816">
          <content>After the second class left, I didn't feel powerful....but I felt successful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="817">
          <content>I had "won"...and so had they.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="818">
          <content>Too often we take a stand in the front middle of the class, and let kids have it.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="819">
          <content>We are in the position of power.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="820">
          <content>Us against them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="821">
          <content>They need to listen to us.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="822">
          <content>They need to follow our rules.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="823">
          <content>They need to do our work.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="824">
          <content>Shift the power next time.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="825">
          <content>Sit down next to "that" kid and see how the conversation changes...make it a conversation instead of a lecture full of coercive threats.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="826">
          <content>Try taking on the "kid" by leveling the field instead of finding ways to employ more heavy artillery.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="827">
          <content>Two things that I have done to level the playing field is to ask a kid to come back with a few of their friends.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="828">
          <content>the other thing that I have done is to walk over to our stair well to talk to a kid.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="829">
          <content>I walk down a few stairs and then turn to talk to them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="830">
          <content>This puts me eye-to-eye, or sometimes it puts me below them-I have to look up.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="831">
          <content>Even if you need to talk to an entire class at once, pull up a chair.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="832">
          <content>Sit down.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="833">
          <content>You will be amazed at how the tone of your entire conversation with them changes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="834">
          <content>Sometimes we get so caught up in getting things done, or moving through curriculum that we forget that we are simply dealing with children, and they have feels, and expectations, and need to be treated with tenderness and respect.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0309wb-03-11034">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="835">
          <content>The teens at Ira H. Hayes Memorial Applied Learning Center have been working on "A Window into Family" for the entire 2004-2004 school year.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="836">
          <content>Through this collaborate process, they have explored different forms of expression, created a trusting and accepting environment for the class to openly and honestly express their individual voices, and learned the technical skills of operating a camera and editing film.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="837">
          <content>This program provides a safe and open space where whatever they want to say is allowed and will be heard.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="838">
          <content>Listening to what they have to say, or what they choose not to say, is essential in forming strong relationships between the students and the teachers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="839">
          <content>The process of creating "A Window Into Family" is an extremely personal and intimate process; we are asking them to share themselves with their peers, elders, family, and complete strangers.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="840">
          <content>Then there are days when they want so badly to be with us and participate in the activities, but they want us to acknowledge them first; they want to know that we value them and want them in the classroom with us.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="841">
          <content>We listen to them, their concerns, wants, and needs, and they play an important part in our lives.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="842">
          <content>Our time with the students in small groups or one-on-one are amazing, and they relax and open up and share so much with us.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="843">
          <content>These are the moments when great work gets done; they stop hiding behind masks and let themselves be them-with all their beautiful qualities and vulnerabilities, and it is wonderful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="844">
          <content>I love more than anything when we catch those truthful and honest moments-it really is so beautiful.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="845">
          <content>We are more productive, on various levels, with smaller groups; the quality of work is better, the level of participation is higher, and the benefits for all of us are greater.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="846">
          <content>Right now we have one Mac at the school, which is wonderful, but it means that only one student can edit at a time, and it takes about two hours to edit one minute of footage.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="847">
          <content>Observing this behavior, I would like to integrate the younger kids into the P:VV program.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="848">
          <content>P:VV could work with the younger kids and the teens together, where the teens would act as teaching assistants in the classroom.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="849">
          <content>It would be a new learning experience for the teens in the program, and would allow P:VV to expand in the community.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="850">
          <content>These two groups working together could learn so much from each other.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="851">
          <content>I have developed trusting relationships with the kids and some of their family members, listened to their stories of their pasts and present, their hopes and fears, and learned how to use a camera and film claymation/animation with them.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="852">
          <content>But regardless of what happens in class, I always leave wanting to come back.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="853">
          <content>I am observing how this program affects these kids, and how it affects myself-it is a wonderful tool of communication between the Gila River Indian Community and the families within this community, and between each individual young adult involved and his/her thoughts and feelings given voice and, therefore, acknowledged.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="854">
          <content>I think this program is effective, important, and necessary to these kids in this community.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="855">
          <content>It allows them to find their strength, gain pride, and a sense of accomplishment; it creates a working safe environment for them to go to, with people who care for them there; it allows them to use their creative energies in various forms, giving tools of expression for their voice to filter through.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="856">
          <content>Having this community -based experience infused into the regular trials and tribulations of the common day allows these young people an outlet for their creative energies and personal feelings.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="857">
          <content>It provides them with the opportunity to be part of a group of respectful and accepting peers, without the judgement, uneasiness, or fear they may endure frequently in their school or social environments.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="858">
          <content>Many of these students come from families that love them very much, but sometimes as a teenager, it is important to have adult role models that are not family.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-1010wb-18-25059">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="859">
          <content>Work with your child's Teacher if you can.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="860">
          <content>There are lots of good schools out there and great teachers who are trying their best in a difficult environment, where lack of resources at the most basic level often hinders their support of differentiated education.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="861">
          <content>Familiarise yourself with the special needs system and what is required to access individual resource hours if that is what is recommended.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0006wb-96-25211">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="862">
          <content>Parents, sisters and brothers, other family members, and teachers can help when someone is being left out or treated in a mean way.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="863">
          <content>They might help by giving you advice on how to deal with mean kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="864">
          <content>Sometimes they can teach kids that it isn't OK to treat others this way and show them ways to stop kids being mean to other kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="865">
          <content>If you or someone you know is being treated meanly or bullied by members of a clique, telling an adult is important.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="866">
          <content>Adults can also help kids learn to play together, include each other, mend hurt feelings, and repair broken friendships.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="867">
          <content>They can encourage kids to make friends and belong to a group without leaving others out.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="868">
          <content>They can show kids how to be popular by treating everyone with respect and kindness.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="869">
          <content>Hang out with kids who aren't part of a clique.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="870">
          <content>Sometimes this means finding older or younger kids to hang out with, or making friends outside school.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="871">
          <content>Sometimes it means being open to kids who look or act differently than you do.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="872">
          <content>Speak up.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="873">
          <content>It's OK to say that you want to invite others to hang out with you, too.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="874">
          <content>Most schools have counselors and policies to help cliques from getting out of hand - maybe you could become an advisor or advocate, or write about it in the school paper.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="875">
          <content>If you're on the outside of a clique and you want to be friends with someone who's in it, invite that person to do something with you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="876">
          <content>Maybe your mom or dad could arrange to have that friend visit at your house on the weekend.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="877">
          <content>If some kids are mean to you because they think you don't fit in, don't let them make decisions about the kind of kid you are going to be.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="878">
          <content>Decide for yourself and then get help to reach your goals.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="879">
          <content>The most popular and well-liked kids are the ones who are friendly to everyone.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="880">
          <content>Do your best to let everyone feel welcome to talk to you.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="881">
          <content>Look for chances to meet, talk with, and play with plenty of different kids.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="882">
          <content>Is someone sitting alone at lunch?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="883">
          <content>Why not ask her to sit at your table?</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="884">
          <content>Or maybe you noticed the kid standing outside the fence while you're playing basketball.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="885">
          <content>It's time to invite him onto the court.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="886">
          <content>Who knows - maybe the two of you will really click (which means to get along really well).</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <document clueWebID="clueweb12-0402wb-89-30864">
      <sentences>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="887">
          <content>One of the things we probably don't want to tell new teachers is that their reward for being able to handle difficult students will be that other difficult students will be transferred to their classes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="888">
          <content>The student was a big behavior problem and was also failing most classes.</content>
        </s>
        <s relevant="true" sentenceID="889">
          <content>Because Cottonwood Press is creating an updated edition of our book Survival Tips for New Teachers , I've been thinking about dealing with difficult kids lately.</content>
        </s>
        </sentences>
    </document>
    <paragraph parID="0">The idea that "everyone's doing it" can influence some kids to leave their better judgment, or their common sense, behind. Walking Away From Peer Pressure Talking to a parent, teacher, or school counselor can help you feel much better and prepare you for the next time you face peer pressure. Powerful, Positive Peer Pressure ALL of us are cutting math. Let's talk about how to handle it. Paying attention to your own feelings and beliefs about what is right and wrong can help you know the right thing to do.</paragraph><paragraph parID="1">Inner strength and self-confidence can help you stand firm, walk away, and resist doing something when you know better. It can really help to have at least one other peer, or friend, who is willing to say "no," too. It's great to have friends with values similar to yours who will back you up when you don't want to do something. If you choose friends who don't use drugs , cut class, smoke cigarettes, or lie to their parents, then you probably won't do these things either, even if other kids do. Try to help a friend who's having trouble resisting peer pressure. It can be powerful for one kid to join another by simply saying, "I'm with you - let's go." Even if you're faced with peer pressure while you're alone, there are still things you can do.</paragraph><paragraph parID="2">You can simply stay away from peers who pressure you to do stuff you know is wrong. You can tell them "no" and walk away. Better yet, find other friends and classmates to pal around with. If you continue to face peer pressure and you're finding it difficult to handle, talk to someone you trust. Don't feel guilty if you've made a mistake or two. For example, positive peer pressure can be used to pressure bullies into acting better toward other kids. If enough kids get together, peers can pressure each other into doing what's right!</paragraph><paragraph parID="3">If you or someone you know is bothered by a bully, talk to someone you trust. Everyone has the right to feel safe, and being bullied makes people feel unsafe. Tell someone about it and keep telling until something is done. Bullying can make kids not want to play outside or go to school. You can't go into hiding or skip class, of course. But if you can take a different route and avoid him or her, do so. Make a plan to walk with a friend or two on the way to school or recess or lunch or wherever you think you might meet the bully.</paragraph><paragraph parID="4">For example, a few kids in school might try to get you to cut class with them, your soccer friend might try to convince you to be mean to another player and never pass her the ball, or a kid in the neighborhood might want you to shoplift with him. Bullying is a big problem. Bullying can make school a place of fear and can lead to more violence and more stress for everyone. If so, you could decide to get up a little earlier so you can be clean and refreshed for the school day. Teachers, counselors, and parents can help. It's hard to keep your mind on schoolwork when you're worried about how you're going to deal with the bully near your locker. As much as you can, avoid the bully.</paragraph><paragraph parID="5">Stand tall and be brave. When you're scared of another person, you're probably not feeling your bravest. But sometimes just acting brave is enough to stop a bully. Stand tall and you'll send the message: "Don't mess with me." It's easier to feel brave when you feel good about yourself. If so, maybe you'll decide to get more exercise, watch less TV, and eat healthier snacks. Or maybe you feel you look best when you shower in the morning before school.</paragraph><paragraph parID="6">Two is better than one if you're trying to avoid being bullied. Offer to do the same if a friend is having bully trouble. Ignore the bully. If you can, try your best to ignore the bully's threats. Pretend you don't hear them and walk away quickly to a place of safety. Acting as if you don't notice and don't care is like giving no reaction at all, and this just might stop a bully's behavior. Stand up for yourself.</paragraph><paragraph parID="7">Pretend to feel really brave and confident. Tell the bully "No! Then walk away, or run if you have to. If a bully wants you to do something that you don't want to do - say "no!" and walk away. Bullies tend to bully kids who don't stick up for themselves. Don't bully back.</paragraph><paragraph parID="8">Don't hit, kick, or push back to deal with someone bullying you or your friends. How can you stop yourself from getting angry or showing you're upset? Try distracting yourself (counting backwards from 100, spelling the word 'turtle' backwards, etc.) to keep your mind occupied until you are out of the situation and somewhere safe where you can show your feelings. Tell an adult. If you are being bullied, it's very important to tell an adult. Find someone you trust and go and tell them what is happening to you. Teachers, principals, parents, and lunchroom helpers at school can all help to stop bullying.</paragraph><paragraph parID="9">Sometimes bullies stop as soon as a teacher finds out because they're afraid that they will be punished by parents. If you have a disability that affects how you learn, you may be put in a mainstream class but be given extra attention to help you learn. If you are in a mainstream class, it is because you, your parents, and your teachers have decided it's the best place for you to learn. If you start out in a mainstream class and then get moved to a special education class, it may be hard to adjust. You are moving to a special education class because you will be able to learn better there. Besides teaching the usual school subjects, many schools also offer special classes for kids with disabilities to help them learn life skills. Figure out where you want to go in life and how you're going to get there</paragraph><paragraph parID="10">But no one needs to put up with a bully's behavior. Or, you may be put in a special education class with other kids who have disabilities. If something is out of your reach or you have a question about the assignment, don't be afraid to ask. Figure out your strengths and needs We think so, but what do we mean when we say "kids with special needs"? This means any kid who might need extra help because of a medical, emotional, or learning problem. You might be able to spot a few kids with special needs, but you probably don't notice all of them.</paragraph><paragraph parID="11">By being a friend. As a teacher/school counselor since 1985, I had a handful of students who really tried my nerves at times. Classroom management is key, but dealing with your own underlying emotions related to a particular student is just as important. So, what to do with kids whose delay tactics include skipping in late, fiddling with their books, and then moseying out of their seats? "Having lots of established procedures is key," says Kate Ortiz. "When the bell rings, everything but [class] materials must be stowed, and there's an assignment on the overhead...usually three or four review questions and it's very effective because it's graded." Ortiz also writes every name on a clipboard and walks around, tallying misbehavior.</paragraph><paragraph parID="12">Dave Foley, a retiree from Michigan with 29 years of experience, wrote the book (literally) on discipline-with chapters that you might appreciate, like, "Using the Stay-After-Class Threat Effectively," or "Using Peer Pressure to Improve Behavior." "The experienced teacher takes it off the table by taking it off the table right away," Burke says. "And you've got to be consistent. If it's Friday afternoon and the kids are taking a test, and the first kid done says, 'Can I listen to my iPod?' If you answer yes, it's a progressive loss of territory.... You don't have to be a jerk. Just say, 'I have to be clear. This is school policy.'"</paragraph><paragraph parID="13">And always follow school policy. Try to commit to two minutes at the beginning of each class to touch base with the often-angry student, Buley suggests. "Prime the pump for the day-ask 'How is the day going to go today?'" Was everybody nice at the bus stop?" For older kids, you could ask, "How has your day been?" Pay attention to the things that make them unique. "When you can talk to them about the fact that they go to the skate park every weekend, you're modeling that they're not a paper cutout."</paragraph><paragraph parID="14">The Time Gobblers If you're a secondary school teacher with a 45-minute period, you know every click counts. They have 10 "self-starting points" a week and they do figure into final grades. And, for those kids who pack up early? Dave Foley, author of the Ultimate Classroom Control Handbook, has a neat trick. With a few minutes left, close the door. Firmly.</paragraph><paragraph parID="15">And say, "We really need to finish this lesson....I'll close the door so you won't be distracted by people passing in the halls." Aaagh! That's prime socializing time! "The core thing is, find out what they don't want to happen and make it a possibility." It is especially important not to corner a kid, especially a potentially violent high school student, as that is when a teacher puts the whole class at a safety risk. If students continued to challenge the school, they were sent to reformatories,Boys Towns, Girls Towns etc. Guidelines were clear and teachers helped students to live by common sense, civil rules.</paragraph><paragraph parID="16">When teachers are told to deal with the situation in such mild "paliative" measures year after year, it is almost an insult as they will continue to waste horrible amounts of time with little success in the classroom until the deeper structural questions are dealt with, like where to put those students who continue to disrupt so the rest of the kids can learn. Anyone who disrupted the class was asked to leave. I have always treated students with respect using the techniques in this article, but in some situations, they simply did not work and I had to be honest about the lack of educational quality offered to those who trully wanted to learn. Teachers can do anything from a simple science experiment or a game that connects students' lives to the lesson. "The teacher who asks challenging questions stimulates student interest. Empower your students by encouraging them to participate in activities of the whole group or in smaller groups." If teachers can start to understand students' cultures better, a partnership can be formed between school and the home with the parents.</paragraph><paragraph parID="17">If the primary problem is one child's behavior, you can talk to him or her in private, but as long as the student isn't disrupting the class, it's not worth stopping instruction to address a situation. As some have already alluded, calling home can be a miracle worker. When groups refuse to work, I telephone their parents at the first opportunity during the day, or send an email. When I telephone home, I make sure that I begin the conversation complimenting what the student does well, and I assure parents that I like their child, enjoy having them in the class; I really praise a student?s excellent qualities; yet, there?s just this one problem... Furthermore, circulating around the class room, "assisting" also works. There's always an assignment they "should be" attempting to complete. When groups decide something other than the immediate task needs to be discussed, I "visit" EACH one, inquire about the status of their assignment, look it over and see if I can offer any suggestions on how to improve, or any general advice pertaining to the completion of the task at hand. When I approach such students, I don?t mention that they are talking and not doing their work.</paragraph><paragraph parID="18">Therein lies my opportunity to assess if they truly understand what they are to do and to motivate them in any way that I can to get it done. Students need to be taught respect from home. I usually take the disruptive student aside and have a one on one conversation. My expectations are restated and for the most part the student understand what is expected and what is not tolerated. The school administration is the key. If their child continues to disrupt class; he parent should be compelled to attend a conference on that student's behalf. In middle school wwe try to teach the student that it is now their responsibility to make the right choices.</paragraph><paragraph parID="19">If they choose to behave that way, they will serve detention, Saturday school, or another appropriate consequence. Now I send each disruptive student an e-mail with a cc to the parent. When the parent is supportive of my role as an instructor, compliance and respect increase accordingly. Are we presenting material in ways that encourage kids to care? After a telephone call home, often there?s a complete personality transformation; a few never disrupt again for the remainder of the school year. So often, just giving them an attn shift seems to do the trick. It's important to keep in contact with the parent,but it's difficult when they don't support you at home.Middle school students are very disrespectful.</paragraph><paragraph parID="20">Teachers will meet and discuss the best alternative for that child, Please note, An IEP or 504 does not mean a parent is off the hook for their child's behavior. I agree with keeping up on parent contacts. It's imperative to let them know what's going on and see if they have any suggestions. I have so many that told me how grateful they were that I had called and let them know! What happened to calling the parents to enlist their support? Complementing the positive traits before discussing the negatives usually worked well. The parents or caregivers eventually admit their appreciation of the mutual support working on behalf of their oppositional students.</paragraph><paragraph parID="21">Kids want to know they are valued. I'm a pro at the Mr. Rogers-style handling of disruptions; however, they are ineffective when it comes to kids who are used to getting their grade just for showing up and turning something in. There is a spectrum of student behaviors and abilities, and each much be dealt with accordingly. SES is much more complex, and things like love and support, not to mention good parenting are worth far more than income. Often, a student merely needs love, support, respect, and more scaffolding to get over the adolescent hump and into the makings of a mature adulthood. Usually, poor schools simply lack the resources to properly assess, diagnose and make proper interventions. Parents need to know what teachers are doing that works best for their child at school and teachers need to know what's working well at home.</paragraph><paragraph parID="22">The rudeness and disruptiveness of students who do NOT want to learn is vicious, deliberate, and, unfortunately, student coordinated when adminstrators refuse to back teachers. In most cases that would let the student know that I was aware of the behavior and not accepting of it. If that didn't work, my next step was to quietly approach the student, kneel down next to him/her and without any anger or alarm in my voice quietly ask the student "Can you behave?" In all the years that I used this technique there were but a handful of episodes where I was unsuccessful at getting the student back on task and acting appropriately for the duration of the class. I might add that a non-cofrontational approach and a low voice that wasn't heard by other students usually allowed the student to save face and return to work without having felt that I "won" and he/she "lost". A teacher in such a situation needs to be given the proper perspective: (1) yes, the administration has created conditions in which students cannot learn, (2) yes, the administration is responsible (read: able to respond) for employing any energetic, heavy-handed behavioral intervention needed, which may involve yanking five disruptive students out of class every day for many days on end (place the burden on them, your administrator, for witnessing and dealing with the conditions they?ve created) and placing the miscreants in independent/solitary study environments elsewhere on campus, (3) yes, the administration is ultimately responsible for maximizing student time on task, and thus maximizing school test scores, and (4) no, a teacher, however talented and adept at employing ? The best strategy is not to let things get out of hand, keeping them engaged.</paragraph><paragraph parID="23">The thought that your child is being bullied is one of the most worrying aspects of being a dad, leaving you feeling powerless, frustrated and unable to help your child. This needn't be the case, however. Even though, by definition, bullying is something that happens to your child when you're not there, there are ways of spotting if your child may be being bullied, and positive steps you can take to bring it to an end. Types of bullying Bullying can take many different forms, the common thread being the perpetrators need to make the victim feel miserable. It doesn't have to mean a child being physically attacked or beaten. Physical : your child being hit, kicked pinched, any form of violence</paragraph><paragraph parID="24">Verbal : name calling, sarcastic comments, cruel teasing Emotional : often more subtle than the above but just as upsetting. Including ridicule, humiliation and exclusion i.e. sending a child to Coventry. CyberBullying : using modern digital communication to send hurtful or threatening messages. Cyberbullying may take place via the internet, on chat rooms or forums, or through text messaging. Warning signs A child who is being bullied may not wish to come to you and tell you about it.</paragraph><paragraph parID="25">Perhaps the bully has warned them not to talk, or perhaps they're buying into the playground code of not telling tales. You can do your best to combat this by creating an atmosphere in which your child knows they can come to you and get a sympathetic and understanding reaction to their worries, but even so, you may first realise your child is being bullied by spotting the warning signs: child is frightened of walking to and from school, perhaps changing their route or begging you to drive them in regularly complains of feeling ill in the mornings, starts missing school or suffers a decline in schoolwork broken or missing possessions a change in sleeping patterns, with trouble sleeping or perhaps bedwetting becoming withdrawn</paragraph><paragraph parID="26">asks for money or perhaps even takes money (the bully may be stealing from them) becomes more agressive than usual, perhaps even bullying other children or younger siblings How to react If you're worried that your child is being bullied then talk to them. They may be reluctant to admit that the bullying is taking place. Reassure them that you will not react to hastily, that you'll stay calm and not do anything to escalate the situation, but that bullying, whatever form it takes, is wrong, is not something they have to put up with, and working together you can tackle it and stop it. Listen to their fears.</paragraph><paragraph parID="27">Make sure they know it's not their fault and they're not alone. Don't put pressure on them to talk. Don't overreact. Your first, understandable, instinct will be to grab the bully by the scruff of the neck. The thought of you acting like this will terrify your child, so stay calm. Simple steps Once you've established that bullying is taking place, there are positive steps you can take:</paragraph><paragraph parID="28">if your child is being bullied at school then contact the school check that they have an anti-bullying policy in place. They are required by law to do so arrange a meeting with the head make notes of the times, places and circumstances of any bullying that has taken place if you are not satisfied with the schools response, then write a letter of complaint to the head of the school, the chair of governors and the Local Education Authority keep a record of all meetings and correspondence</paragraph><paragraph parID="29">ensure that the school takes action, maintaining contact and pressure until you are satisfied On a more general note, help your child to practice strategies for dealing with bullies, such as shouting "No!" , walking or running away, meet with other parents to discuss the problem - they may be suffering similarly and a united front can make things easier to tackle Self Defence Classes - Not merely teaching your child to fight back. self defence classes often boost a child's confidence, making bullying less likely Understand that it is okay to express anger. Attack the problem, not the person.</paragraph><paragraph parID="30">Recognize that dealing with conflict is not about winning or losing, but about behaving in the right way." Work together on problem resolution. Communicate your anger management and problem-solving skills with your children. Share specifics of how you've dealt with anger. Why Do Some Kids Dislike School? If you don't like school, the first step is finding out why. First, write down everything you don't like about school.</paragraph><paragraph parID="31">Then make a list of the good things you enjoy (even if it's only recess and lunch, that's a start!) Now, what can you change on the "don't like" list? When you stop to think about why you don't like school, you can start taking steps to make things better. It's a good idea to talk to someone about your problems with school. Your mom, dad, relative, teacher, or school counselor will be able to help you. It's especially important to tell an adult if the problem is that you're being bullied or someone hurts you physically. Another good idea is to write down your feelings about school in a journal.</paragraph><paragraph parID="32">You can use a journal or diary or just write in an ordinary notebook. It's a great way to let out emotions that may be stuck inside you. If you feel disorganized or like you can't keep up with your schoolwork, your teachers and school counselors want to help. Teachers want and expect you to ask for help learning stuff. If all of your subjects seem really hard, a school counselor can help you sort things out. Special help with schoolwork is available if you need it. Try not to let the problems go on too long.</paragraph><paragraph parID="33">It's easier to catch up on one chapter than the whole book! The next time you find yourself disliking school, try this: Would remembering to do your homework help you feel more confident if you're called on in class? Can you get help with schoolwork that's hard? Who can you talk to about a worry or problem you're dealing with? Could you find a way to show off your special interests and talents? If you made just one new friend, would you feel less alone?</paragraph><paragraph parID="34">If you helped someone else feel less alone, would you feel even better? Which activities could you try that would help you meet new friends? Of course, you might not be able to change everything on your "don't like" list. Focus on what you can change and you might be able to put the cool back in school! Talk to an adult you trust, such as a parent, guidance counselor, or both. Give it time. You may not feel immediately comfortable with your teacher, but that may change as you get to know one another.</paragraph><paragraph parID="35">If you've given it time, talk with your parents about what to do next. Lots of times, a meeting can be set up to discuss the problem. The stress of dealing with bullies can make kids feel sick. Some bullies are looking for attention. When they pick on someone else, it can make them feel big and powerful. Some bullies are copying what they've seen someone else do. Some have been bullied themselves.</paragraph><paragraph parID="36">Bullying: How to Handle It Don't give the bully a chance. Feel good about you. Get a buddy (and be a buddy). Fighting back just satisfies a bully and it's dangerous, too, because someone could get hurt. Plan ahead. Dealing with difficult kids</paragraph><paragraph parID="37">Even if you love your students and are great at your job, a classroom full of the school's problem kids is not easy for any teacher. I discovered an interesting approach to the problem when I was teaching. My theory was this: in a classroom of low-achieving students, the student's behavior would be rewarded. The kids would likely egg him on. In the honors class, the kids would not encourage him. They would help keep him in line. And, while he might not be working at the same level as the other students, he would likely learn more than he would in a class where his time was spent acting out.</paragraph><paragraph parID="38">He tried, at least some of the time, which was a great improvement over the past. A difficult student in an honors or gifted class always proved much more manageable than a difficult student in a "regular" class or a class of low achievers. The counselor also wants to help you learn as much as you can in class, be a contributing member of the school community, and be a positive influence on your environment. The counselor will try to help you figure out what's going on. Your appointment with the counselor could happen during the day when classmates might notice you're gone. I was not a skipper, which I am actually very grateful for, even though 7th grade was the worst year of the bullying, because I have always been one of the three most-young students in my class, before the skippies at Uni. Demanding social skills from 11 year olds is not exactly reasonable.</paragraph><paragraph parID="39">Most people remember their social experiences from high school more than their calculus final or their history paper. Shouldn't one goal of any high school, including Uni, be to *help* students develop socially? If Uni turns down a student who is lacking in so-called common sense, that child will surely face more trouble in public high schools. Why should Uni discriminate against people based on their ability to communicate? Communication can be taught just as well as any other subject; its as if you're suggesting to exclude all applicants who score low on math exams. Boy, what a nasty wake-up call by the world. Looking back, even though middle school was the worst part of my short life, I was not ready for high school.</paragraph><paragraph parID="40">to stay at Urbana Middle School would have probably been bad because i wasnt ever challenged, and not fun at all comapred to Uni. some people started out life too mature (okay just really mature for their age) and over time got more immature to fit with their age group. I bet that within each class, if you just look at how each student performs behaviorally and academically, you wouldn't be able to tell who skipped a grade and who didn't. I skipped a grade when I came to Uni and I don't feel that I would be any more prepared had I come a year later. "No student is going to lose anything by not skipping a year, by completing seventh grade in a regular middle school." Had I skipped a year, I would have been one of the youngest people in that class (July 91). Our point of writing the editorial was to question the usefulness of having students skip a grade.</paragraph><paragraph parID="41">We just believe that developmentally, it would be beneficial for most students to not skip a grade. Also, bear in mind that Lizzy did skip, and Lauren and I didn't, but we all share the opinions expressed in the editorial. Statement 1: Are students who skip a grade expected to grow up too fast? Response 2: The professors on campus who hire students of mine to work during the summer report better reliability and work performance from those who've skipped a grade, and are more likely to hire those students again than their older counterparts. Statement 5: No student is going to lose anything by not skipping a year, by completing seventh grade in a regular middle school. Based on our own observations, parents of students who skipped a grade tend to be the ones who most fit this description. Without considering the input of my parents, I made the decision to skip.</paragraph><paragraph parID="42">Skipped Certainly, I would not advise just anybody to skip. It is imperative that students who skip are mature if they wish to flourish. Fundamentally, students who skip must be socially mature. Secondly, they must be the ones to make the decision. Lastly, they must be able to handle the workload and maintain their competitive status in a class of significantly older students. After graduating last year, I'm currently taking transitional (or "gap") year.</paragraph><paragraph parID="43">I spent the summer relaxing and the fall traveling abroad while simultaneously completing volunteer hours and an internship. In the winter, I applied to colleges. I plan on spending the spring raising money for college and writing a book. I also hope to continue to grow as a person and become secure in my future plans. Most of these opportunities would have been impossible had I not skipped. Concerning what I read of this article, I think the article's main fault is its generalities. The choice to skip or not should be made according to the development of the person.</paragraph><paragraph parID="44">There are 18 -year-old graduates with the maturity of a five-year-old and there are 16-year-old graduates with the maturity of someone twice their age. Eighteen is, by no means, the cutoff age for childhood nor is it the guaranteed age for intellectual or social maturity. Adolescents develop at all different ages. Certainly not all parents of children who skipped are overly protective, pushy, or restrictive. My parents were supportive of my decision without treating me any different than if I hadn't skipped. The majority of parents just want what is best for their child. Sometimes a non-conventional education is best.</paragraph><paragraph parID="45">I really have no clue how this age gap effects Uni students, but I assume they have an easier time than I did being that they are the minority instead of the exception. Based on my experiences, the only non-successful students I know who have skipped are those that did not give skipping enough consideration. Conversely, the majority of students I know who have skipped are more mature and stable than their older counterparts. This is probably due to the fact that they had to work slightly harder not to fall behind. As a future Journalism major, I want to randomly mention my amazement at the quality of the Gargoyle as a whole, its articles, and the mature debates that take place within its comments section. I agree with Mr. Stone in that the skipping situation tends to be more complicated than is shown in this article, and the projected solution is an intriguing idea but essentially flawed. I'd especially like to highlight that a 7th grade year can be worse than going to Uni early.</paragraph><paragraph parID="46">This is definitely what I thought when applying: Mahomet schools left me socially starved and educationally bored, not the ideal situation for a fragile 11-year old. For this reason, I can't fully regret leaving Mahomet at that point. However, not having my liscence until Senior year and graduating at the age of 16 are two aspects I'm not looking forward to, and reflecting on Subbie year, I was unfortunately particularly immature. So faced with these observations, I would propose, not a weeding out of younger students, but an enforcement of the awareness that there IS a down-side to skipping a year. The idea that skipping is sometimes also the best idea socially is defiantly true. I moved here from Pittsburgh after my sixth year, and if I had started at Urbana Middle School I would have had a much harder time making friends. Because I came into this school at the same time everyone else in my grade did, I was able to focus more on studies (Not that subfreshmen year was hard or anything...).</paragraph><paragraph parID="47">I agree that skipping does create some problems. However, both Mr. Stone and Andrew presented excellent reasons to keep grade skipping as an option. I don't think interviews should be introduced into the admissions process. I can't remember if there were questions on the teacher reference forms about maturity and behavior, but maybe these issues can be addressed more directly in the forms that teachers are asked to fill out. The admissions committee already takes some care to consider this issue, but maybe it should be given even more emphasis. I would like to add that it's not always the youngest students who are the most immature! The real problem is simply that the local middle schools are so terrible.</paragraph><paragraph parID="48">If so many kids didn't feel the need to escape, then skipping would be rare. Ideally, I would prefer that the subbie year be discontinued, and the class size for grades 9-12 increased. There are too many qualified students who are not accepted. But as long as so many bright students are miserable in middle school, the subbie year should remain and skipping should be an option. My congratulations to the Gargoyle editorial staff for tackling another complex issue. But I think it is important that we all realize that the issues of skipping are hardly new. "Skipping," or ending up a year ahead of one's peers in school, has been going on for decades, and is not inherently the problem.</paragraph><paragraph parID="49">His mother was given the choice of letting him go to kindergarten or first grade. For our daughter, if she makes it in, we hope she will have the opportunity to be a part of a school where being an intelligent female is not a liability socially, and a place were her musical abilities and interests can be nurtured. The issue of being "dispositionally suited" for an academic program is one we also face at the college level. As my colleague Mr. Stone has noted, though, you have made some rather broad generalities and have not necessarily done all your homework. Academic research rather overwhelmingly supports skipping for academic reasons as more beneficial than remaining for social/maturity reasons. Check the academic research, not just your personal opinion/observation. The grinding issue is not ignored in "public" schools.</paragraph><paragraph parID="50">Again, do some research. Much of the issue at Uni, I would note, had less to do with the Subbies than with the fact no faculty wanted to chaperon dances with grinding. No chaperons = no dance, right? Jason He -- for whom I have infinite respect -- is wrong when he suggests the admission is split 50/50 by grade level. It is split 50/50 by gender. And having been on the committee, I can verify that much thought goes into the maturity level of the student. Any indication on teacher recs to the contrary is an immediate and important red flag.</paragraph><paragraph parID="51">Interviews, which have been discussed recently, bring up multiple issues with the name-blind admission process, an important -- and often overlooked -- part of the admission process. I know Uni isn't seen to be a social school but I think skipping a grade can really hurt future social skills. I didn't skip, and while my two years at Franklin may not have been the most academically challenging they opened me up to numerous cultures and issues, and I had a lot of fun. Yell, attention to troublemakers, intimidation, ridicule, or the opposite-a pushover. The other thing I have observed and my kids have observed even more is that many teachers show little to no tolerance in the classroom towards kids with special needs. This is then handed down to the other kids. What kids will show compassion and caring towards kids that the teacher gets angry with, shows contempt towards and sometimes even ridicules in front of the classroom.</paragraph><paragraph parID="52">We're going to take a walk and get lunch instead. As you grow older, you'll be faced with some challenging decisions. In this series, I have had the privilege of interviewing other homeschoolers from across the country. Here to tell us how her family got started homeschooling and what her family's homeschool style looks like is Rachel. They homeschool using a virtual school, a cyber school where the kids' learning takes place online. How long have you been homeschooling? We started homeschooling our older child in a very organized way when she was just 5.</paragraph><paragraph parID="53">Our younger child was 3 and a half at the time, and we homeschooled her in a more laid-back way (a lot of sitting in on sis's lessons, lot's of reading, some math DVD's that first year). We are completing our second year now - and this year both kids have a very organized style of schooling. How/why did you get started homeschooling? The bricks and mortar public school is excellent, and they very much wanted to help and accommodate...but were clearly unable to. Private schools were unable to deal with their special needs either. They offered to try, everyone was nice, but everyone was honest too. We stumbled across virtual schooling on the internet!</paragraph><paragraph parID="54">It is a VERY tech-y and early computer use program, which is in line with our parenting style. I also like that we get report cards, progress reports, and the school keeps up with IEPs. The school also welcomes lots of parental input on IEPs, and all of it can be done over the phone in a conference call, which is very freeing. For someone just coming out of public school would he or she expect to go straight into their same grade in the virtual school or are the students placed in the appropriate level for each subject they take? They will assess for another skip this next fall (after she starts as a 3rd grader) to 4th grade, as she has completed half of her 3rd grade courses, and by fall she will have completed all of her 3rd grade work. AND classes can be radically higher in one subject and lower in another (to accommodate a strong reader who struggles with math, or vice versa). AND they will skip a child once per year as needed.</paragraph><paragraph parID="55">In the lower grades, "as needed" is proved by finishing the year's work by early spring or earlier. Entered as a kindergartener, assigned 1st grade work across the board, finished that in late winter, now in 2nd grade work, and was skipped a grade halfway through the year. However, all that said, for children in upper grades, grade placement depends on more extensive testing, and children may be officially skipped (or possibly demoted to a more appropriate lower grade) as determined. I don't know a lot about that, I just know it's different from the early grade levels. The flexibility with grade skipping and grade level work being done is the biggest plus with this program in my opinion. She sends stickers, notes, and bookmarks in the mail sometimes. I would say they communicate with her about twice a month, not counting class connects.</paragraph><paragraph parID="56">Do your kids have interaction with other kids in the program or just with the teacher like you talked about above? My kids' main contacts with other kids in the program is in the online guided class sessions called "class connects." Class connects are every couple of weeks for history. Those taper off near the end of the year as more students are either preparing for yearly testing (there are class connects for those too) or catching up on subjects they've gotten behind in. The virtual school does field trips quite often. Since my kids are young and VERY active, we skip long drives whenever possible. So your kids have virtual connections... how much interaction do your kids have with other homeschoolers in your area?</paragraph><paragraph parID="57">I would say half of their friends are homeschooled and half are in standard schools. Our virtual school is actually a public school by law in our state, so our only cost is $500 per child to attend school out of county. She has one subject now that she can more or less do independently, without me constantly hovering! I offer some choices, but they are choices like "would you like to do history and science today or would you like to do two history lessons today and two science lessons tomorrow?" Short and sweet should be the punishment, not for long periods but I also like the 'making amends' idea like an apology and letter if needed. Make sure that your child is capable of doing the class work he is being asked to do, for example. Being behind (or ahead of) the class can create boredom, frustration, and anxiety-which may lead some kids to act out verbally or physically.</paragraph><paragraph parID="58">Understand that in this case, giving consequences is far less important than figuring out what your child needs to do differently the next time he wants to act out. In other words, if you say, "You have to stay in your room because you acted out in school today," you're not addressing the behavior and it will not help your child because you're not teaching him anything-except how to do time. Sometimes parents assume that their kids will figure out things on their own, but if you're dealing with a chronic issue, you have to face facts: your child has not figured it out by himself and he is not likely to do so. Be realistic in your goals: When you structure your child's study time to help him bring his grades back to an acceptable level, be realistic in your goals. On the Support Line, I've found that when parents really make a consistent effort to keep up with their kids, they are seldom caught unawares when it comes to dropping grades or poor school performance. It's no secret that failing to attend school can lead your child or teen to become involved in risky behaviors, especially if he is not supervised consistently at home. If your child skips school chronically, you may have to involve community services and ask them to address the underlying reasons for school truancy.</paragraph><paragraph parID="59">Problems at School? How to Handle the Top 4 Issues Acting out in school When your child acts out in school , it can be worrisome, frustrating and embarrassing. On top of the actual misbehavior, you fear that he'll make a bad name for himself-that his reputation as a troublemaker will follow him from grade to grade. You may also feel judged-and blamed-by teachers and other parents for what your child does at school. Some kids act out when they're feeling left out or left behind.</paragraph><paragraph parID="60">I want to stress that for the most part, you should not give consequences for school misbehavior at home, unless your child is damaging school property or hurting others physically. That's because punishing your child at home is not going to give him the skills he needs to behave more appropriately. In some cases, letting the school hold your child accountable is enough, but in chronic or severe acting-out situations, it will be important to work with the school to get of what is going on. You may then need to work with some local supports to address the behavior. But for the most part, leave discipline for acting out at school to school officials-don't punish your child twice. You need to help him. So talk to the teacher-that's your best first step.</paragraph><paragraph parID="61">Take it from there. You need a sense of why he's acting out and what's happening in order to know how you can help your child change. And pay close attention to what your child is saying at home; he should know that all experiences are okay to share. A word of caution: One important lesson James Lehman teaches us is to support the school authorities in front of your child. If your child hears your criticism of school officials and his teachers, he is likely to be disrespectful to them in class-and also to you, later on down the line. If your child's grades are dropping, rule number one is to become an investigator. In other words, really find out what's going on with your child.</paragraph><paragraph parID="62">Is he having problems at home or with other kids at school? Is he having a tough time adjusting to middle school or high school? Are his study habits poor-and can you work on that together? For some kids, learning disabilities and medical problems may play a role. And for still others, drug and alcohol use may be the cause of falling grades. The main thing for you to do is find out the "why" and then come up with a plan to help your child. Here are some steps you can take immediately:</paragraph><paragraph parID="63">Meet with your child's teacher: Call your child's teacher and ask for a meeting. Tell her what you are seeing at home-and then ask what she has observed in the classroom. Ask her for any ideas she might have to help your child get back on track. Set up more structure at home. A common problem for many kids is a lack of structure in their after school schedule. Make sure sports or other clubs do not come first, with homework being fit in at the end of the day (when your child is exhausted). This is not a good lesson to teach your child because it gives them the message that play comes before work-and is therefore more important than work.</paragraph><paragraph parID="64">Clubs or sports should not come before school work and family time for your child. The bottom line is that schoolwork has to be prioritized, and a structure has to be set up so it isn't squeezed in at the last minute. Remember, it took time for your child to get behind, so you need to allow time for him to catch up. Get actively involved in your child's homework by reviewing it and helping with study strategies. I also recommend that you try to be present during study time. I know that many parents work and can't be at home with their children after school. If you or your spouse can't be there, try to get your child into in an after school program or ask another trusted adult to be there with them.</paragraph><paragraph parID="65">Don't restrict your child from privileges until his grades improve. Understand that restricting your child from all of his privileges until he brings his grades up usually backfires. In effect, you end up taking away something that might actually motivate your child to improve. Instead, I recommend that you require your child to study for a certain amount of time each day to earn those extras that night. Talk to your child about what's going on. Have a frank conversation with your child about his grades. Say, "Look, I've been letting you manage your homework on your own, but it's not working.</paragraph><paragraph parID="66">Now we're going to set up a study time every day where I supervise your work. We can talk about not doing that once your grades get back up where they need to belong. But in the meantime, we have to seriously set aside some time to work on this." And remember to ask your child about his day and show that you are interested; ask questions that require a longer answer than "yes" or "no." If your child is skipping school-either playing sick or skipping out of classes-again, you first need to investigate and find out why. Is your child failing, being bullied, under the influence of alcohol or drugs, or does he have physical problems? Some kids develop anxiety around going to school; they can have stomach aches or headaches as a result.</paragraph><paragraph parID="67">A lot of kids will say they're sick in order to avoid school because they have anxiety about it. If there's an anxiety issue at play, a visit to your child's pediatrician to determine whether counseling is in order might be your best course of action. A skilled counselor can gently get your child over the hump and teach them ways of coping with their nervousness around school. So the reason why your child is missing school chronically needs to be understood so it can be resolved. For example, if your child is being bullied , you will need to work with the school to make sure your child is protected and that it stops. The juvenile justice system does not like the idea of kids skipping school and loitering around town, so there may be hope there. You might call up your local police department and say, "I can't get my child to go to school.</paragraph><paragraph parID="68">Are there any resources available in this community to help me get him back on track?" Understand that if your child is chronically skipping school, it's usually the result of a problem that has built up for quite some time. Often it's the end of a long string of problems, rather than the beginning. For this reason, I believe this is an issue that's important to nip in the bud at an early stage. So when your child's grades start dropping or he's coming home moody and sad, intervene then. Keep the communication open and always stay interested in what's happened to your child from day to day-it will pay off in the end, I promise you. Discussions don't work, encouragement/rewards don't work, withholding of privileges doesn't work, and they don't have conflicts with ohter commitments.</paragraph><paragraph parID="69">I have to agree with some of these comments about still punishing at home for school consequences. Only being driven by consequences and threatening. As both parent and teacher, I agree with one of the main points, that of finding out what the main problem is behind the negative behaviors, but I disagree that there should be no further consequence at home for poor choices kids make at school. Don't get me wrong, teaching is an incredibly reflective practice, but sometimes (especially when I'm working with particular types of groups that spend their time away from school doing god knows what), I've found it easier to leave thinking about it in my class. Once they verbalize whatever's getting their goat, they're usually good to go. Others may be pressured to take risks like steal, pull pranks, or bully other kids in order to stay in the clique. Perhaps the most important thing that helped me get through these years was support, which I found in both books and people.</paragraph><paragraph parID="70">Raising Your Spirited Child: A Guide for Parents Whose Child is More Intense, Sensitive, Perceptive, Persistent, Energetic Kids, Parents and Power Struggles: Winning for a Lifetime . The Difficult Child , by Stanley Turecki with Leslie Tonner While the written word can provide a lot of information, there is no substitute for an understanding ear, especially if you are fortunate, as I was, to find someone who has specific insight into dealing with a "hard" child. Another key I learned in dealing with my child was acceptance. My child was and is more difficult than average; in fact, he was so far at one end of the spectrum that his father and I at times considered the possibility that he was beyond "normal," and that we may need professional help. In any case, we believed that informed, careful and determined parenting was his best hope for helping him learn to get along in the world.</paragraph><paragraph parID="71">(If you don't have a way to develop resources to deal with this kind of child, or if your child appears "over the edge" to you, getting professional help may be called for.) If you are dealing with a difficult child and you haven't seriously considered how diet, sleep and television are affecting your child, I encourage you to examine how adjusting diet, helping to insure the most rest possible, and limiting or foregoing "screen time" might improve things for your family. Additionally, while Tom had a difficult time going to sleep, was a poor napper, and did not "sleep through the night" until he was five, we still kept up our warm bedtime routine and started plenty early so that even if it took him a long time to go to sleep, he would be well rested the next day. Like we did, you may find that the actual medium of television, not just its content, is something that is best avoided or limited with difficult kids. This may help with a parent's acceptance of how "different" the child seems from her childhood self. i am a single mum of a six year old boy, and i need help as i do not know what to do anymore, his got a very bad temper, he reply me and his teachers at school.He beats up kids at school, and that scares me, cause not every parent is the same. He disturbs the class and does not do his work, and his very bright...am scared sometimes to pick him up from school as i think he did something bad.I talk to him everyday before school, but nothing seem to change...please help!!!!!!</paragraph><paragraph parID="72">These books helped to reframe a child's negative qualities as positive ones (a "stubborn" child may be thought of as "determined," an "inflexible" child has "focus"), and they offered specific strategies for dealing with intense children. Well-meaning acquaintances or relatives, and even some professionals, can have a toxic effect when they are dismissive of our concerns or offer simplistic solutions: "I'd just spank him until he knows who's boss" or "My children wouldn't dare do that!" While dealing with a demanding child seems to leave no energy for anything else, it has been absolutely worth the effort to seek a supportive mentor or group to help. It was easy enough to keep a jug of water, fruit and bread in the car. We found that very little to no television was our best bet in helping him manage as a two- and three-year-old. I also highly recommend you signing up for a class called Parent Project. Teacher had mentioned in passing early in the year that maybe they should be split up.</paragraph><paragraph parID="73">2 weeks ago, other mom had a meeting with principal because of a few more incidents and he agreed to switch her son to a different class. The principal, teacher and another teacher all made a point of saying to me that G did nothing wrong and that this boy was not really being very nice to him. Not a good excuse for that kind of behavior....especially in adults but sometimes we're so overwhelmed that it comes out like that. Trails wants those kids who are lost in the middle, the ones not previously identified as either the problems or the superstars. Those invisible kids are the ones that need Trails for they are the ones in danger of falling through the cracks." Kathleen Milligan is a Master Practitioner of NLP and a member of the NLP Canada Training Advisory Board. Her practice includes children who have yet to be born (she works with fertility clients and moms-to-be) and many more who have hit bumpy spots and been referred to her by schools, doctors or other practitioners.</paragraph><paragraph parID="74">She combines hypnosis, NLP, EFT and energy psychology in a unique blending that helps children connect with their strengths and with the people around them. Allow each child to enter your room with a clean slate. Give them an opportunity to re-invent themselves. Let them start over. This school year, as you attempt to change kids' behaviors and attitudes, you'll do well to remember the concept of successive approximations. This concept holds that behavior and attitudes will change gradually and slowly. Progress will often be plodding.</paragraph><paragraph parID="75">But you must recognize and reinforce each step toward the target behavior. But, on a day when she only interrupts six times, you must praise and reinforce her effort and progress. But you must reinforce him every time he canters, trots, or skips. You cannot wait until he walks appropriately before praising him. You must reinforce each bit of progress and effort, or the progress and effort will stop! Every one of your students is somebody's child. Give them the dignity and respect that you would want for your own kids.</paragraph><paragraph parID="76">Read the kids' files and seriously consider the input and opinions of the teachers who worked with the child in the past. Who is to say that the English teacher might not have a great idea about how to get the kid to show up on time for his math class? Therefore, the poor speller disrupts the spelling bee; the kid with verbal difficulties acts up during class discussions; the student with math difficulties gets thrown out of his algebra class. R - Reward direction, not perfection This school year, as you attempt to change kids&#65533; behaviors and attitudes, you'll do well to remember the concept of successive approximations. Remember : Hurt people hurt people. Don&#65533;t take it personally.</paragraph><paragraph parID="77">In a few weeks, twenty-five sets of parents will be entrusting you with their most precious possession &#65533; their child. They are not dropping off their air conditioner or their lawn mower for repair, they are giving over the care of their baby. You must view this trust as a sacred and humbling responsibility. Quite simply, there is no greater privilege or responsibility that one human being can give to another than to surrender temporary care of their child. Take this responsibility seriously. But, it is realistic to expect you to treat your students with the same respect and sensitivity that you would hope that your kids&#65533; teachers would give to them. Every one of your students is somebody&#65533;s child.</paragraph><paragraph parID="78">You would hope that the teacher would stop and provide your child with the care and comfort that s/he needs. So do it for somebody else&#65533;s kid. Parents surrender their child to you with the expectation of in loco parentis . You are the parent in the parent&#65533;s absence. We need to drastically modify our approach and adopt a transdisciplinary model to our teams. When twelve highly trained professionals and the child&#65533;s parents sit around a table, you have a virtual treasure chest of wisdom, training, and experience present. Transdisciplinary meetings allow the team members to "take their uniforms off."</paragraph><paragraph parID="79">They are no longer at the meeting to defend, represent, and protect their departments - they are there to defend, represent, and protect the student . I promise you will find that transdisciplinary meetings are lively, stimulating, productive - and effective. We discuss important issues and solve real problems. Solutions are based upon the child&#65533;s best interests, not on the needs of the adults. I never feel more like a professional than when I sit around that table." At any given moment, any kid would prefer to be viewed as a bad kid rather than a dumb kid. Children, particularly adolescents, live daily in paralyzing fear of being embarrassed in front of their peers.</paragraph><paragraph parID="80">If they are put in the position of looking bad or looking dumb , they will invariably choose to look bad . This year, if a child is acting consistently "bad," reflect for a moment: are your approaches and activities making him look "dumb?" If they are, he will choose to look "bad" and disrupt the activity in an attempt to prevent his weakness from being displayed for all to see. Before you change the child&#65533;s behavior, maybe you need to change your own. She constantly told us to try new strategies and approaches and avoid getting in a "classroom rut" when you use the same materials and methods year after year after year. Try different approaches. Modify your methods.</paragraph><paragraph parID="81">Keep your teaching fresh! Read the kids&#65533; files and seriously consider the input and opinions of the teachers who worked with the child in the past. BUT don&#65533;t let these reports shade your opinions about (and treatment of) that child. So let&#65533;s make a commitment to deal more effectively and sensitively with these kids who struggle with learning every day through no choice or fault of their own. These kids need a commitment in time, energy, and resources. They don't learn, they need to be taught . You cannot pick and choose the difficulties that you will accept or that you will reject.</paragraph><paragraph parID="82">You can&#65533;t say, "I understand he has difficulty reading, but I will not tolerate his continually losing his homework." Some children require a visual approach; others need auditory methods. Some students benefit from structured phonics; other students require a more language-based approach. This school year, make a commitment to provide sensitive support on the kids&#65533; "bad days" and to embrace, celebrate, and maximize their "good days." Try to be a sentry against this hopelessness. Let your classroom be the one place where they feel safe, secure, and valued. Demonstrate that you accept them and provide them with much needed attention and affection.</paragraph><paragraph parID="83">Small, unsolicited (and often undeserved) acts of kindness can do much to soften and reach the troubled child. A smile, an encouraging note, a positive comment on the top of a homework assignment, asking about his dog, greeting him at the classroom door, a hand on his shoulder, using his nickname, or sending him a postcard from your vacation can truly make a difference. Don&#65533;t take this behavior personally. Rather, continue to provide him support and warmth. Parents can get in big trouble when their kids skip school , sometimes even facing fines and jail time themselves. Recently in Florida, a law was passed that states that parents can go to jail for up to two months when their children (age 16 and under) skip school repeatedly, missing more than 15 days in one three-month period. Are parents to blame when their children skip school, or should the kids be held accountable - or does the answer lie somewhere in the middle?</paragraph><paragraph parID="84">A STUDENT should bear the responsibility for not going to school if they are skipping. If a parent SENDS the child the parent should not be held accountable for the child skipping out. Unfortunately this was in November, it is now January, he has run away twice, continued using drugs and drinking, and skipping. My son skipped school a lot during his high school years and it took him an extra year to complete his high school education. I'm pretty sure it's the rare parent that sits back and does nothing, allowing their kid to skip school when ever they choose. My son is 14 and has made a habbit of skipping (staying home from) school regularly over the past 3 years. and how can a parent know or stop them from skipping when maybe they have work in the morn' and don't see them go to school or they assume they do stay at school when they ride the bus there</paragraph><paragraph parID="85">Now in Kentucky, lawmakers have decided to turn the tables: In the town of Covington, minor students can be arrested on misdemeanor charges for playing hooky - and if their parents are complicit, they can be taken in along with their kids. Officers have an option of giving kids a warning, taking them home, or booking them if the child is suspended or has been expelled, and the parents can't be reached. It's the child who needs held accountable for their actions. If the parent is allowing it, not sending them etc. that's another story What happened with my own son is he was brought before an attendance panel which in Alberta is a division of the Court of Queens Bench. They were highly proffessional and accomodating, and believed my son could do better. He owned up to his indiscretions, assured the board it would not continue.</paragraph><paragraph parID="86">The school knows me quite well and have been working with me consistantly. We meet again before the attendance board next week and there are some other options hopefully that they can make available, I will plead on my son's behalf and offer solutions to a problem I cannot seem to fix. Situations are different - it can be the parents fault or it can be the kids fault - it all comes down to the details - why should there be a law across the board? Its a battle everyday - we are exhausted but were consistent with our expectations - the school has been of no help what so ever - I think if I was sent to jail for this I would end up going in for murder instead for the judge that would actually rule this in our situation. I have a question though - if the parents went to jail - what happens with the kids? maybe it's worth the trip! He hated school, struggled with academics, and felt that he was a misfit.</paragraph><paragraph parID="87">Struggles with school led to isues with self esteem. Since leaving school he has done much better. His self esteem is greatly improved and he has learned through successes in life that he is not stupid. Recently he ran in to a teacher who had labelled him lazy and incompetent and he told the teacher how he felt as a child when he was ridiculed in the classroom in front of peers for the struggles that he was having. Recently my son wrote me a card thanking me for always believing in him and being there for him as he struggled through his teen years. I do not support a system that would charge children and parents across the board with non attendance without addressing the issus that are keeping them away. My experience is that many of the parents of children who struggle in school also struggled in school themselves.</paragraph><paragraph parID="88">I had an agreement with the school that if she missed anymore time, she was supposed to get an in school suspension, which isn't happening, and she has now run away from home and is staying with different friends. I think that if I could have her arrested and put in "jail" for a day or two, it might just be enough to curb the behaviour and get her back on track. Penalizing a parent that is already feeling pushed to the limits by a "difficult kid", just seems wrong. In our case sending our son to jail for a stint might just be beneficial. The school has been involved and helpful as much as they can, but truly, until he decides to change, nothing we do or say is going to get him there. Dealing with school Meet with teachers.</paragraph><paragraph parID="89">Point out any special needs, like having to go to the bathroom frequently. Meet with coaches and other appropriate staff, too. Make sure the school has written health care instructions, such as medication schedules, special diet needs, your pediatrician's contact information, and emergency plans. Encourage her to speak up . If she can't see something, has a question, or just needs a little extra support, the teacher is there to help. Reassure her if she needs special education classes. If a girl is moved out of a mainstream class, make sure she understands that this is done to help her learn better.</paragraph><paragraph parID="90">The move is not a punishment or sign there's something wrong with her. Ask the school to provide work if she misses class. If a child will be out for a long time, find out about special tutors or online lessons. Ease her transition back to school after a long absence. If she's going to have special needs after her absence or if she might look different, work with her on what she can say to classmates. Ask her if she'd like to have the school nurse tell classmates what to expect. Children with certain conditions may qualify for special services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA).</paragraph><paragraph parID="91">An Individualized Education Program (IEP) lists the kinds of special help a student will receive. These might include having extra time on tests, sitting in the front of the class, or special tools (called "assistive technology") like talking calculators or Braille keyboards. To qualify for an IEP, a child needs to have an evaluation by education professionals. Special teachers, parents or guardians, and the child all are important parts of the team that writes the IEP. You can invite anyone who works closely with your child to participate in making the plan if you think they can help. If you think the services aren't working well, you can ask for a team meeting. If you think a child's education rights aren't being met, you have options, including asking for an official hearing.</paragraph><paragraph parID="92">If you think you need a lawyer, you can ask the school district about low-cost or free legal services. Students provide only positive feedback about The City, describing it as both stimulating and fun. "Any time you can incorporate technology into your class, they'll eat it up." Student 1: It definitely wasn't something that you normally see in school and most of the stuff you do is pretty boring, and this was interesting and interactive. I liked it. One of the techniques that The City uses to draw students in and make it more stimulating and engaging is they have introduced eight characters and they are at different life stages. Any time you can incorporate technology into your class, they'll eat it up.</paragraph><paragraph parID="93">I don't want to do it just because it "seems cool." Finding Help And you don't have to share what you've written with others. Feeling Better About School They are the "Saturday kids" - the kids who are confident and competent on Saturdays, summers, and school vacations, but are frightened and frustrated when they enter the classroom. "Back to school" routines have been a part of my life for most of my Augusts as a student, a teacher, a dad, a school administrator, and now as a school consultant. The first day of school represents something of a rebirth.</paragraph><paragraph parID="94">They hold tightly to the belief that "if I can't see the teacher, the teacher can't see me." You may choose to ignore the behavior but you can't ignore the underlying need. Teachers recognize that we must use a variety of approaches to teach reading because children learn to read in a variety of ways. However, many teachers will attempt to motivate all thirty, unique and disparate students in the class by using one, solitary approach. Teachers must also use a variety of motivational approaches. There are six basic "drives" that inspire students to strive toward their fullest potential. One of the most common - but least understood - difficulties experienced by struggling students is performance inconsistency.</paragraph><paragraph parID="95">This school year, make a commitment to provide sensitive support on the kids' "bad days" and to embrace, celebrate, and maximize their "good days." Before you change the child's behavior, maybe you need to change your own. You should also remember that September marks a "New Year" for your students, too. Give them an opportunity for a fresh start. Don't let difficulties or issues from last year spill over into this year. Wipe the slate clean. BUT don't let these reports shade your opinions about (and treatment of) that child.</paragraph><paragraph parID="96">Let him begin the school year with a clean slate. You might not like school because a bully is bothering you, or because a kid you don't like wants to hang around with you. Maybe the work is too easy and you get bored. Or maybe the work is too hard, or you don't feel as smart as the other kids. In Algebra II, remember to do group work, and do more " participation quizzes " during that group work. The point would be to add a more "cultural" component to the class, and a lot of my kids love reading and learning about tangents. In Algebra II, remember to utilize the Park School of Baltimore curriculum , especially when working on Quadratics, Transformations, and Exponential Functions.</paragraph><paragraph parID="97">It didn't quite fit in with our 2nd quarter material, but it will align with our 3rd and 4th quarters. In Algebra II - since we don't have a midterm for students to see a broad view and get a review of all the 1st and 2nd quarter's material - have the 3rd and 4th quarter problem sets include "review problems" from topics from the first semester. Or if not, have review problem assignments, in addition to the problem sets. In Calculus, continue having kids work in groups on challenging problems every so often. Their schools work really hard to help every student succeed, but they don't have the resources that my school had to help the kids who can really do more. Sometimes, kids and grown-ups have difficult problems. They help students handle almost any problem that could get in the way of learning, guide them to productive futures, and try to create a positive environment for everyone at school.</paragraph><paragraph parID="98">Perhaps you just found out that your parents are getting divorced , or your dog just died, and you're so upset that you can't concentrate on doing your homework. Counselors Help You Cope Today, counselors are called upon to help students in a broader way. These are all subjective, pejorative labels that attempt to describe in medical terms various states of acting or being, visible emotional turmoil or ways of perceiving the world that do not fit into the arbitrary mold of 'normalcy'. Home   |   iAssist   |   Admin 4 City Hall Plaza, Chaska, MN 55318  |   (952) 448-9395   |   Carver County Copyright 2012 by Carver County Library and JFD Dealing With Kids' Setbacks Some days it just seems all too much.</paragraph><paragraph parID="99">You get a call from the school about an incident with your son. Or your daughter comes home defiant and tearful. And whatever you do seems like the wrong thing. Well, it's probably not. The right thing to do isn't always the perfect thing. Or rather, you don't need to find the perfect solution to do something that helps. If you're like most parents (and by most parents, I mean, me) you don't routinely hit the ball out of the park.</paragraph><paragraph parID="100">There's a fair amount of trial and error involved. And it's even more of a challenge as your child gets older. We usually do too much or too little. But it helps when you start to understand that this is the way it works. Raising children, and especially children with special needs, is a constant state of discovering what - and how much -- to do. For one thing, you never know how much independence they can handle until you give them too much. It's sort of like being in a sailboat.</paragraph><paragraph parID="101">Whatever your destination, you're constantly dealing with winds trying to blow you off course. You often have to tack back and forth, not always able to steer exactly toward your goal, but constantly getting closer, until you reach it. Just as we can't usually sail directly to our goals, we often can't help our kids solve problems immediately. But if we keep providing course corrections and don't get discouraged, we can help them make steady progress. Of course, sometimes it's hard not to get discouraged. And sometimes we're too close to an event to see the better courses of action. So we need to be careful about making decisions affecting the future in a fury of frustration.</paragraph><paragraph parID="102">"We're never going to a fast food restaurant again!" or "I'm going to call that child's mother and give her a piece of my mind!" Radical solutions can sometimes do more harm than good. Better to wait and look at the problem with the perspective a little time can give, even if it's only an hour or a day. And it always helps to step outside the problem and look at it objectively. What caused the problem? What can you or your child do differently?</paragraph><paragraph parID="103">If you need to convince your child to do something different, what incentives can you come up with? Focus on how he can get something he wants if he takes a certain course of action. And success is an amazing teacher. If a child tries something and it works, she'll almost always put it in her bag of tricks. In my experience, negative consequences tend to shut down kids' minds. But even stubborn minds tend to seek out pleasure and the prospect of positive results. Be careful of getting dragged down into a contest of wills.</paragraph><paragraph parID="104">"Because I say so," is not a convincing argument. And kids often find creative ways around obeying ultimatums. You've got to be the parent. You may not be smarter than your kids (I know this first-hand), but you have more experience. And you have a secret weapon. You love them even when they lose control. They may be overwhelmed by the moment and frozen in injustice or disappointment or hopelessness.</paragraph><paragraph parID="105">But adults tend to understand that there are few things more powerful than knowing someone cares about you and believes in you no matter what. Just listening to their frustration or anger can help defuse it. Have you ever seen your child so upset that he didn't want anyone suggesting solutions? You just don't UNDERSTAND! It's an insult to suggest there was anything else he could have done! It was just UNFAIR! By staying calm, you can help the storm pass.</paragraph><paragraph parID="106">You can be the safe haven. You can repair the torn sails and restock the ship and supply fresh navigation charts. And give your child the confidence to try again. Belief is a powerful force. If you convince your daughter she can succeed, her chances of reaching a goal go up dramatically. Sometimes, belief is everything. My wife has an uncle (Uncle William) who had a setback as a high school junior.</paragraph><paragraph parID="107">When he got his report card at the year's end, it said he'd flunked -- and would have to repeat the 11th grade. William anxiously had a friend take the report card to his mother while he went to his after-school job delivering telegrams. When he got home, he found his mother had fixed him his favorite dinner, fried chicken, and baked him a big apple pie. And she didn't say a word about his report card that night. The next day, they sat down together and came up with a plan. In spite of being scared, William went alone to the school and negotiated an agreement that he could go on to the 12th grade with his class if he retook some key courses in summer school and passed. He did just that.</paragraph><paragraph parID="108">And he went on to succeed in college and graduate school. Today, Uncle William is a respected minister and community leader. Love and understanding can see you through the toughest times and give your kids a lifelong example to follow. So, the next time your child has a setback, you have an opportunity. You can understand that setbacks are not an interruption of the process, they're part of the process. However you decide to help, it can be the right thing even if it's not the perfect thing. And you can't go wrong with apple pie.</paragraph><paragraph parID="109">You can find more articles on his website at: www.coultervideo.com . Accepting the situation helped me develop strategies that resulted in Tom's improvement and in the ability to get our family through the day. For instance, while experiments with the Feingold diet did not bring about improvements for our son, many parents find children's behavior vastly better when they eliminate certain chemicals, additives and food dyes. We eat few of those anyway, and we continued to find that general good nutrition emphasizing whole foods and no caffeine did make a difference, as did paying particular attention to anticipating our son's inability to cope with hunger and thirst. We never allowed Tom to watch such action-packed television as The Power Rangers. Finally, my experience in talking to parents of difficult toddlers and preschoolers is that a large majority of them are boys. Mothers especially may benefit from reading and thinking about gender differences in young children.</paragraph><paragraph parID="110">This is a great topic to get Dad's insight on as well. And finally, it may help you come up with creative ideas for channeling your son's energy. Believe it or not, Tom was using a real hammer and nails at his own wooden workbench-wearing eye protection-before he turned three. Had you ever looked into the Hand in Hand parenting technique. They have a website and have classes that talk about techniques to help. Also they have support groups and 'listening partnerships' A school counselor or your friends also can be helpful to you.</paragraph><paragraph parID="111">Get organized. What did you eat at school? Every night before going to school or other activities, you can go over the checklist and make sure you have the snacks and medicines you'll need for the next day. But it's better for everyone if homeschooling isn't chosen just as an escape from school or problems there, such as bullying . A great person to share your thoughts and feelings with is your school counselor. Add school counselors to the list of people you can turn to when you need help. Your school counselor is available for you and wants to make your school experience the best it can be.</paragraph><paragraph parID="112">The counselor's job is to take your problem seriously and help you find a solution. If someone was bullying you, for instance, the counselor would talk to you about it and could give you some ideas and strategies on how to deal with the bully. If you'd prefer not to miss class time, ask the counselor if you can talk before school, at recess, during lunch, study hall, or after school. What Else Do Counselors Do? I'm not talking about throwing out discipline and consequences. I'm talking about applying the rules with compassion and making accommodations while you help a child see things from a perspective that's foreign to him. About trying to find out what a child is thinking and why she acts the way she does.</paragraph><paragraph parID="113">It's not enough to tell these kids the rules, because their brains are operating from a separate set of rules that seem right to them. About seeking help if dealing with a special needs child, along with other children, becomes overwhelming. What if we live by the approach adopted by the mission control crew in the movie "Apollo 13," when three astronauts' lives were at stake? "Failure is not an option." If your child acts up, don't bend the rules, but understand what feelings may be motivating that behavior. What is the difference between a teacher who gets to know their kids, and one who keeps their distance? Do you think you would treat you kids differently if they got to know you better?</paragraph><paragraph parID="114">Would they respond differently to you if your relationship with them was stronger? If you had to speak to a kid how would the conversation be different if they were next to you, instead of across the classroom? I wasn't happy with some of the kids and their work on an assignment we had just done...and I was in a blame them mood. I rattled off a list of kids that I wanted to meet with "after class." At the end of the period most of the class left and those on the list remained at their seats. Out of the bowels of my old teacher self came all sorts of threats, what are you all thinking, and this is not how you want to continue in this class sort of comments. I felt strong afterwards for being that demanding teacher who did not let them slide.</paragraph><paragraph parID="115">I had won, they left defeated. I started off the same way, I rattled off a list of names. Proceeded with class. Class ended, and most of the class filed out and only the kids who I named were left behind...but they were not in their seats. Without any prompting on my part they left their seats and came up right up close and stood in front of me, and on the sides...I was nearly surrounded. They were too close for the heavy artillery. My heavy duty comments and yelling were long distance weapons, to be used when I was in power in the front of the room, and when they were in their seats...where they belong.</paragraph><paragraph parID="116">Now they were close, they had cornered me in a corner of the room in neutral territory. This was too close for any of the heavy duty weapons in my arsenal, I had to shift to winning hearts and minds. I spoke softly, was supportive, developed plans to assist them, and tried to give them what they needed to be successful...options that I missed the first time. There were even...smiles. After the second class left, I didn't feel powerful....but I felt successful. I had "won"...and so had they. Too often we take a stand in the front middle of the class, and let kids have it.</paragraph><paragraph parID="117">We are in the position of power. Us against them. They need to listen to us. They need to follow our rules. They need to do our work. Shift the power next time. Sit down next to "that" kid and see how the conversation changes...make it a conversation instead of a lecture full of coercive threats.</paragraph><paragraph parID="118">Try taking on the "kid" by leveling the field instead of finding ways to employ more heavy artillery. Two things that I have done to level the playing field is to ask a kid to come back with a few of their friends. the other thing that I have done is to walk over to our stair well to talk to a kid. I walk down a few stairs and then turn to talk to them. This puts me eye-to-eye, or sometimes it puts me below them-I have to look up. Even if you need to talk to an entire class at once, pull up a chair. Sit down.</paragraph><paragraph parID="119">You will be amazed at how the tone of your entire conversation with them changes. Sometimes we get so caught up in getting things done, or moving through curriculum that we forget that we are simply dealing with children, and they have feels, and expectations, and need to be treated with tenderness and respect. The teens at Ira H. Hayes Memorial Applied Learning Center have been working on "A Window into Family" for the entire 2004-2004 school year. Through this collaborate process, they have explored different forms of expression, created a trusting and accepting environment for the class to openly and honestly express their individual voices, and learned the technical skills of operating a camera and editing film. This program provides a safe and open space where whatever they want to say is allowed and will be heard. Listening to what they have to say, or what they choose not to say, is essential in forming strong relationships between the students and the teachers. The process of creating "A Window Into Family" is an extremely personal and intimate process; we are asking them to share themselves with their peers, elders, family, and complete strangers.</paragraph><paragraph parID="120">Then there are days when they want so badly to be with us and participate in the activities, but they want us to acknowledge them first; they want to know that we value them and want them in the classroom with us. We listen to them, their concerns, wants, and needs, and they play an important part in our lives. Our time with the students in small groups or one-on-one are amazing, and they relax and open up and share so much with us. These are the moments when great work gets done; they stop hiding behind masks and let themselves be them-with all their beautiful qualities and vulnerabilities, and it is wonderful. I love more than anything when we catch those truthful and honest moments-it really is so beautiful. We are more productive, on various levels, with smaller groups; the quality of work is better, the level of participation is higher, and the benefits for all of us are greater. Right now we have one Mac at the school, which is wonderful, but it means that only one student can edit at a time, and it takes about two hours to edit one minute of footage.</paragraph><paragraph parID="121">Observing this behavior, I would like to integrate the younger kids into the P:VV program. P:VV could work with the younger kids and the teens together, where the teens would act as teaching assistants in the classroom. It would be a new learning experience for the teens in the program, and would allow P:VV to expand in the community. These two groups working together could learn so much from each other. I have developed trusting relationships with the kids and some of their family members, listened to their stories of their pasts and present, their hopes and fears, and learned how to use a camera and film claymation/animation with them. But regardless of what happens in class, I always leave wanting to come back. I am observing how this program affects these kids, and how it affects myself-it is a wonderful tool of communication between the Gila River Indian Community and the families within this community, and between each individual young adult involved and his/her thoughts and feelings given voice and, therefore, acknowledged.</paragraph><paragraph parID="122">I think this program is effective, important, and necessary to these kids in this community. It allows them to find their strength, gain pride, and a sense of accomplishment; it creates a working safe environment for them to go to, with people who care for them there; it allows them to use their creative energies in various forms, giving tools of expression for their voice to filter through. Having this community -based experience infused into the regular trials and tribulations of the common day allows these young people an outlet for their creative energies and personal feelings. It provides them with the opportunity to be part of a group of respectful and accepting peers, without the judgement, uneasiness, or fear they may endure frequently in their school or social environments. Many of these students come from families that love them very much, but sometimes as a teenager, it is important to have adult role models that are not family. Work with your child's Teacher if you can. There are lots of good schools out there and great teachers who are trying their best in a difficult environment, where lack of resources at the most basic level often hinders their support of differentiated education.</paragraph><paragraph parID="123">Familiarise yourself with the special needs system and what is required to access individual resource hours if that is what is recommended. Parents, sisters and brothers, other family members, and teachers can help when someone is being left out or treated in a mean way. They might help by giving you advice on how to deal with mean kids. Sometimes they can teach kids that it isn't OK to treat others this way and show them ways to stop kids being mean to other kids. If you or someone you know is being treated meanly or bullied by members of a clique, telling an adult is important. Adults can also help kids learn to play together, include each other, mend hurt feelings, and repair broken friendships. They can encourage kids to make friends and belong to a group without leaving others out.</paragraph><paragraph parID="124">They can show kids how to be popular by treating everyone with respect and kindness. Hang out with kids who aren't part of a clique. Sometimes this means finding older or younger kids to hang out with, or making friends outside school. Sometimes it means being open to kids who look or act differently than you do. Speak up. It's OK to say that you want to invite others to hang out with you, too. Most schools have counselors and policies to help cliques from getting out of hand - maybe you could become an advisor or advocate, or write about it in the school paper.</paragraph><paragraph parID="125">If you're on the outside of a clique and you want to be friends with someone who's in it, invite that person to do something with you. Maybe your mom or dad could arrange to have that friend visit at your house on the weekend. If some kids are mean to you because they think you don't fit in, don't let them make decisions about the kind of kid you are going to be. Decide for yourself and then get help to reach your goals. The most popular and well-liked kids are the ones who are friendly to everyone. Do your best to let everyone feel welcome to talk to you. Look for chances to meet, talk with, and play with plenty of different kids.</paragraph><paragraph parID="126">Is someone sitting alone at lunch? Why not ask her to sit at your table? Or maybe you noticed the kid standing outside the fence while you're playing basketball. It's time to invite him onto the court. Who knows - maybe the two of you will really click (which means to get along really well). One of the things we probably don't want to tell new teachers is that their reward for being able to handle difficult students will be that other difficult students will be transferred to their classes. The student was a big behavior problem and was also failing most classes.</paragraph><paragraph parID="127">Because Cottonwood Press is creating an updated edition of our book Survival Tips for New Teachers , I've been thinking about dealing with difficult kids lately.</paragraph></documents>
  <query>dealing with kid that skip classes</query>
</singleQueryResults>